(BELLS TOLLING)
昨晚  我梦见自己又回到了曼陀丽庄园
MRS. DE WINTER: Last night,I dreamt I went to Manderlay again.
恍惚中  我站在那扇通往车道的大铁门前
It seemed to me I stood by the iron gate leading to the drive,
好一会儿被挡在门外
and for a while,I could not enter,for the way was barred to me.
进不去
这时  我突然像所有的梦中人一样
Then,like all dreamers,
不知从哪儿获得了超自然的神力
I was possessed of a sudden with supernatural powers
幽灵般飘过面前的障碍物
and passed like a spirit through the barrier before me.
车道在我眼前伸展开去
The drive wound away in front of me,
蜿蜒曲折  依稀如旧
twisting and turning as it had always done.
但是待我向前走去  就察觉到车道已起了变化
But as I advanced,
I was aware that a change had come upon it.
原来自然界已恢复了本来的面目
Nature had come into her own again,and littla by little
渐渐把她细长的手指顽强而偷偷摸摸地
had encroached upon the drive with long,tenacious fingers.
伸到车道上来了
即使在过去  树林对车道来说  也始终是个威胁
On and on wound the poor thread that had once been our drive,
终于到达了曼陀丽
and finally,there was Manderley.
曼陀丽  还是和过去一样的隐僻  静谧
Manderley,secretive and silent.
时光的流逝  丝毫无损于围墙的完美对称
Time could not mar the perfect symmetry of those wells.
我看见那一泓银色的海水
Moonlight can play odd tricks upon the fancy,
犹如风平浪静时明镜般的湖面
静静地任月光爱抚
and suddenly it seemed to me that light came from the windows.
一朵乌云已经遮没了月亮
And then a cloud came upon the moon
乌云有好一阵子徘徊不去  就像一只黑手遮住了脸庞
and hovered an instant like a dark hand before a face.
顿时  幻觉消失了
The illusion went with it.
我遥望远处孤零的小屋
I looked upon a desolate shell
闪闪的墙上未留下一丝岁月的痕迹
with no whisper of the past about its staring walls.
曼陀丽不再为我们所有
We can never go back to Manderley again.
曼陀丽不复存在了
That much is certain.
但有时在我的梦里
But sometimes in my dreams,I do go back
我确实重回到我生命中奇怪的日子
to the strange days of my life
那是从在法国南部开始的
which began for me in the South of France
不  别跳
No! Stop!
你在嚷嚷些什么
What the devil are you shouting about?
你是谁  你看什么呢
Who are you? What are you staring at?
对不起  我不是有意偷看的  但我 我只是以为
I'm sorry,I didn't mean to stare,but I... I only thought...
你有意的  对吧  你在这儿干吗
Oh,yon did,did yon? Well,what are you doing here?
我只是在散步而已
I was only walking.
那就继续散步吧  别处在这儿乱嚷嚷
Well,get on with your walking. Don't hang about here screaming.
我再也不会在淡季来蒙特卡洛了
I'll never come to Monte Carlo out of season again.
酒店一个知名人物也没有
Not e single well-known personality in the hotel
咖啡凉了  服务员  侍者  叫人
Stone cold. Waiter!
让他拿些
Gargon! Call him. Tell him to get me some...
天哪  是迈克斯・德温特  你好啊
Why,it's Max de Winter.
How do you do?
-你好  -我是伊迪丝・范・霍珀
很高兴在这儿碰到你
I'm Edytde Van Hopper. It's so nice to run into you here,
我刚刚开始绝望  在蒙特
just when I was beginning to despair of finding any old friends here in Monte.
一个老朋友都没碰到
坐下来喝杯咖啡吧
But do sit down and have some coffee.
德温特先生要跟我一起喝咖啡
Mr.de Winter is having some coffee with me.
叫那个愚蠢的服务生再倒一杯
Go and ask that stupid waiter for another cup.
恐怕我非得同您抵触一下不可
I'm afraid I must contradict you.
是你们二位同我一道用咖啡
You shall both have coffee with me.
-服务生  咖啡  谢谢  -是  先生
Gargon. Coffee,please.
-抽烟吗  -不  谢谢
-Cigarette? -No,thank you.
你一进餐厅我就认出你了
You know I recognized you as soon as you came in,
虽然那晚在棕榈滩的赌城见过就没再见了
though I haven't seen you since that night at the casino at Palm Beach.
也许你不会记住像我这样的一个老妇人
Perhaps you don't remember an old woman like me.
你有在这儿玩桥牌吗
Are you playinp the tables much here at Monte?
不玩了  恐怕那只是几年前我用来消遣的玩意
No.I'm afraid that sort of thing ceased to amuse me years ago.
我很理解你  对我来说
I can well understand that.
如果我能拥有一座像曼陀丽一样的仙乡
As for me,if I had a home like Manderley
我肯定绝不会来蒙特
I should certainly never come to Monte.
那是国家最大的地方之一
I hear it's one of the biggest places is that part of the country,
你会被那儿的美景深深吸引住
and you just can't beat it for beauty.
你觉得蒙特卡洛怎么样  或是你根本就不屑于它
What do you think of Monte Carlo? Or don't you think of it at all?
我觉得过于匠气
Well. I think it's rather artificial.
她被宠坏了  德温特先生  这就是她的毛病
She's spoiled,Mr.de Winter that's her trouble.
多少姑娘情愿把自己的眼睛作代价
Most girls will give their eyes for a chance to see Monte.
换得看一看蒙特的机会
Wouldn't that rather defeat the purpose?
这样一来不是达不到目的了吗
现在我们再次相遇
Now that we've found each other again,I hope I shall see something of you.
希望能不时见到你
你一定得到我房间里来坐坐
You must come and have a drink in my suite.
我想他们一定给你弄了个好房间
I hope they've given you a good room.
地方很空  所以要是你觉得不舒服  听着  别慌
The place is empty,so if you're uncomfortable,mind you make s fuss.
你的行李  侍从总给料理好了吧
Your valet has unpacked for you,I suppose?
我没有侍从  也许您愿意为我去打开行李吧
I'm afraid I don't possess one. Perhaps you would like to do it for me?
我 我可不是说
Well,I... I hardly think...
假如需要
Perhaps you could make yourself useful to Mr. de Winter
也许你能帮帮德温特先生的忙
if he wants anything done.
你在许多方面都是个能干的孩子
You're a capable child in many ways.
好极了  但是我信奉我家的老话
That's a charming suggestion,but I'm afraid I cling to the old motto,
"单身旅客行路最快"
“He travels fastest who travels alone.” Perhaps you've not heard it. Good night.
也许您从来没有听说过这句话吧  晚安
多滑稽啊
What do you make of that?
你觉得他唐突地离开是不是一种幽默
Do you suppose that sudden departure was intended to be funny?
走吧  别傻愣在那儿  上楼吧
Come,don't sit there gawking,let's go upstairs.
-你有带钥匙吧  -带了  范・霍珀太太
-Have you got the key? -Yes Mrs.Van Hopper
我记得曾经有一位出名的作家
I remember,when I was younger,there was e well-known writer
每见我走来就绕道而走
who used to dart down the back way whenever ha saw we coming.
我看他大概对我着了迷  可又缺乏自信
I suppose he was in love with me and wasn't quite sure of himself.
这就是生活啊
Well,c'est la vie.
顺便说一下  亲爱的  别怪我又数落你
By the way,my dear,don't think that I mean to be unkind,
不过你在德温特先生面前毕竟是个小人物
but you were just a teeny-weeny bit forward with Mr. be Winter.
你竟想独揽大家的谈话
Your effort to enter the oouversation quite embarrassed me,
这使我很尴尬  我敢说他也有同感
and I'm sure it did him. Men loathe that sort of thing.
男人是不喜欢这种样子的  好了  别不高兴
毕竟我要对你在这儿的行为负责
Oh,come,don't sulk. After all,I am responsible for your behavior here.
也许他没有注意到  可怜的孩子
Perhaps hedidn’tnotice it.
Poor thing,I suppose he just can't get over his wife's death.
我想他只是无法从他妻子过世的事里走出来
他们说他非常爱她
They say he simply adored her.
(MAN LAUGHING)
(CUTLERY CLINKING)
是
我真失礼
Oh... How awkward of me.
看我干的蠢事  对不起
What a stupid thing to do. Oh,I'm so sorry.
别麻烦了  真的没关系
Please don't bother. It doesn't really matter.
让它去吧  去我桌上添一副刀叉
No,leave that,leave that. Go and lay another place at my table.
-小姐跟我共进午餐  -这可绝对不行
-Mademoiselle will have lunch with we. -Oh,but I couldnn't possibly.
-为什么  -请不必客气  你人真好
-Why not? -Oh,well,please don't be polite. I...
不过只要侍者把桌布换一下  就没事了
It's very kind of you but I'll be all ripht if they just change the cloth.
我不是同你客气
I wasn't being polite.
即使你没有冒冒失失地撞翻花瓶
I should have asked you to have lunch with we
我也会邀请你的
even if you hadn't upset the vase so clumsily.
Come along.
来吧  要是不愿意  我们不一定要说话
We needn't talk to each other if we don't feel like it.
非常感谢
Well,thank you very much.
我要些炒鸡蛋就行
Oh,I...I'll just have some scrambled eggs.
是  小姐
Oui,mademoiselle.
你朋友怎么了
-What's happened to your friend? -She's ill is bed with a cold.
她感冒了  卧病在床
对不起  我昨天的举止太不成体统
I'm sorry I wss so rude to you yesterday
对此  我只有一个借口
The only excuse I can offer is that I've become boorish through living alone.
单身生活使我变成了粗鲁的乡巴佬
谈不上粗鲁  你只不过想要单独
You weren't really. You simbly wanted to be alone and...
告诉我  范・霍珀太太是你朋友还是只是雇主关系
Tell me,is Mrs.Van Hopper a friend of yours or just a relation?
不  是雇主  我就是所谓的有偿伙伴
No,she's my employer.I'm what is known as“a paid companion.”
我倒不知道伴侣还能花钱买呢
I didn't know companionship could be bought.
我曾在字典里查"伴侣"这个词
I looked at the word“companion” in the dictionary once.
释义说"伴侣就是心腹朋友"
It said,“a friend of the bosom.”
我不妒忌你的特殊待遇
I don't envy you the privilege.
她真的很友善  我得谋生
Well,she's very kind,really,and I have to earn my living.
-你没有家人吗  -没有  我妈妈很多年前就去世了
Haven't you any family?
No. My mother died years and years ago,
然后就只剩我父亲
and there was only my father,and he died last summer.
去年夏天他也去世了  然后我就找了这份工作
And then I took this job.
-对你打击很大  -是啊  打击颇大
How rotten for you.
因为我们关系很好
Yes it was rather,because,you see,we got on so well together
你跟你的父亲吗
You and your father?
对  他生前就是一个既可爱又不同凡响的人
Yes. He was a lovely person,very unusual.
-他做什么的  -他是位画家
-What was he? -A painter.
-他画得好吗  -我觉得很好
Ah! Was he a good one?
但世人不理解他
Well,I thought so,but people didn't understand him.
是的  艺术家的困扰
Yes,that's often the trouble.
他画树  至少那是一颗树
He painted trees. At least,it was one tree.
你是说他一直重复画同样的树?
You mean,he painted the same tree over end over again?
是的  他有个理论如果你发现一件完美的事物
Yes. You see,he had a theory that if you should find one perfect thing
或是地方或是人  你就该坚持
or place or person,you should stick to it.
很蠢吧
Do you think that's really silly?
哪儿有  我是个坚信自我的人
Not at all. I'm a firm believer in that myself.
他在画树的时候
And what did you find to do with yourself while he was painting his tree?
你干吗那
Well,I sat with him and I sketched a little. I don't do it very well,though.
我坐在他身边  然后画点素描  虽然我画得不好
-下午你要去画素描吗  -是的
Were you going sketching this afternoon?
-去哪儿画  -我还没想好
Yes.
-Where? -Well,I haven't made up my mind.
-我开车载你去  -不用了  谢谢  我不是
I'll drive you somewhere in the car.
Oh,no,I didn't mean...
废话不多说了  快吃完  我们走吧
Oh,nonsense. Finish up that mess,and we'll get along.
谢谢  你人真好  但我不是很饿
Thank you.It's very kind of you,but I'm not very hungry.
快吃  像乖孩子一样吃完
Come on. Eat it up like a good girl.
你画蛮久了
You've taken long enough for that sketch.
我期待一副艺术作品出炉
I shall expect a really fine work of art.
不要  别看  画得一点都不好
Oh,no,don't look at it. It's not nearly good enough.
但也不至于那么差吧
Well,it can't be as bad as all that. Nowbss’tmb it all sat.
快给我看看  别擦掉  先让我看看
Let me see it first.
-是透视画法  我永远画不好  -让我瞧瞧
Well it's the perspective. I never can get it right.
Let me see it,let me see it. Oh,dear.
亲爱的  告诉我  是透视画法
Tell me,is it the perspective that gives my nose that curious
让我的鼻子中段被画得歪歪扭扭的吗
twist in the middle?
-你作为素描模特不大容易画  -不容易吗
Well,you're not a very easy subject to sketch.Your...
-你的表情一直在变  -有吗
Your expression keeps changing all the time.
Does it?
我是你的话  就会专心于画风景
Well,I'd...I'd concentrate on the view instead,if I were you.
那更值得一画
Much more worthwhile.
它使我想起我们家的海岸线
It rather reminds me of our coastline at home. Do you know Cornwall at all?
你知道康沃尔吗
知道  放假的时候  我跟爸爸去过那儿
Yes,I went there once with my father on holiday. I was in a shop once,
我在一家商店看到过一张明信片
and I saw a postcard with a beautiful house on it,right by the sea.
上面印着一座坐落在海边的美丽房子
我问那间房子是谁的  那个老太太说  那是曼陀丽庄园
I asked whose house it was,and the old lady said,“That's Manderley.”
-我为自己的无知感到羞愧  -曼陀丽很漂亮
I felt ashamed for not knowing.
对我来说  那只是我出生的地方罢了
Manderley is beautiful.
But to me,it's just the place where I was horn,
而且要在那里终其一生
and have lived in all my life.
但现在  我不知道该如何去面对它
But now,I don't suppose I shall ever see it again.
我们很幸运  天气恶劣的时候没在家
(STUTTERING)We're lucky not to be home during the bad weather,aren't we?
在英格兰直到6月才能尽情游泳
I cent ecer remember nn)nying nmimming in Englend till June,nun ynn9
这儿的水很暖  所以我可以整天待在里面
The water's so warm here that I could stay in all day.
那儿的回头浪很危险  去年有个男人在这儿淹死了
There's a dangerous undertow and there was a man drowned here lest year.
我对溺水从来都不觉得恐惧  你呢
I never have any fear of drowning. Have you?
走吧  我载你回家
Come,I'll take you home.
是的  我认识德温特先生  我也认识他太太
Oh,yes,I know Mr.de Winter well. I knew his wife too.
她结婚之前  可是漂亮的丽贝卡・希尔德莱思
Before she married she was the beautiful Rebecca Hildreth,you know.
当她在曼陀丽附近航行的时候淹死了  可怜的女人
She was drowned,poor dear,while she was sailing near Manderley.
他从不谈论此事  但他的心全都碎了
He never talks about it,of course,but he's a broken man.
你最好该吃药了  真恶心
I suppose I'd better have it.
给我块巧克力  快点
Wretched stuff! Give me a chocolate,quick!
你来了啊  正是时候
Oh,there you are.It's about time.
快点  我想玩拉米纸牌
Hurry up. I want to play some rummy.
漂亮的丽贝卡・希尔德莱思
EDYTHE: She was the beautiful Rebecca Hildreth,you know.
他们说他非常爱她
They say he simply ahored her.
漂亮的丽贝卡・希尔德莱思
She was the beautiful Rebecca Hilbreth,you know.
我想他只是无法从他妻子过世的事里走出来
I suppose he just can't get over his wife's death.
漂亮的丽贝卡・希尔德莱思
She was the beautiful Rebecca Hilbreth,you know.
但他的心全都碎了
But he's a broken man.
-你好  -你要去哪儿
Bonjour
-我想去上网球课  -知道了
-Well,where are you going? -I thought I'd take a tennis lesson.
我猜你已经看到教练了  他帅呆了
I see.
I suppose you've had a look at the pro,and he's desperately handsome,
你肯定幻想着什么爱情故事吧
and you've conceived a schoolgirl crush on him.
好了  去吧  好好享受吧
All right. Go ahead. Make the most of it.
-下班了吗  -是的
Off duty?
范・霍珀太太从感冒变成流感了
Well,yes. Mrs.Van Hopper's cold's turned into flu,
所以她请了位专业护士
so she's got a trained nurse.
真替那位护士感到难过  你喜欢打网球?
I'm sorry for the nurse. You keen on tennis?
不是  不是特别喜欢
-Well,not particularly -That's good.We'll go for a drive.
那太好了  我们去游车河
下午好  范・霍珀太太  感觉怎么样
Good afternoon Mrs.Van Hopper. How are you feeling’?
你跟他处得不错啊  是吧
You got on rather well with him,didn't you?
除了网球  那个教练肯定还教了你其他东西吧
That pro must have been teaching you other things than tennis.
快点  我要打几个电话
Hurry up,I want you to make some calls.
我想知道德温特先生是否仍在酒店
I wonder if Mr.de Winter is still in the hotel.
亲爱的德温特先生
你这讨厌鬼  怎么也不回我电话
我保证  等这恼人的感冒一好
我就会把你从蒙特卡洛这无聊的地方解救出来
因为我知道  你此刻一定无聊至极
无聊  无聊  无聊  伊迪丝・范・霍珀敬上
我可以走了吗
May I go now?
你已经上过多堂网球课了
For the number of lessons you've had,you ought to be ready for Wimbledon.
你该准备去温布尔登(网球锦标赛)
但这是最后一堂课了  尽情享受吧
But this will be your last,so make the most of it.
麻烦的是  像我这样卧病在床  你没什么事可干了
The trouble is,with me laid up like this,you haven't had enough to do.
但今天我要退掉护士
I'm getting rid of that nurse today.And from now on,you'll stick to your job.
并且从现在开始你将重归工作岗位
是的  范・霍普太太
Yes,Mrs.Van Hopper.
-护士  -是的  范・霍珀太太
-Nurse? -Yes,Mrs.Hopper?
你确定给德温特先生留言了吗
Are you absolutely sure you left those messages for Mr.de Winter?
-怎么了  是的  夫人  -我只是不敢相信
-Why,yes,madame. -I simply can't believe it.
他一定会回我电话的
He would most certainly have called me back.
可怜的孩子  我实在不忍看他孤身一人
Oh,well. Poor boy,I simply hate to see him so alone.
我 我希望能有种发明
You know,I... I wish there could be an invention
能把记忆像香水一样装在瓶子里多好
that bottled up the memory,like perfume,and it never faded,
记忆就永不褪色  常年新鲜
never got stale.
什么时候需要  只要随时打开瓶子
Then whenever I wanted to,I could uncork the bottle
你就仿佛又回过头去重新体验那一刻
and live the memory all over again.
有哪些特别的时刻  你想重新体验呢
And what particular moment in your young life would you want to keep?
所有  过去几天的所有时刻
All of them. All these last few days.
我仿佛要 要收集满满一整架瓶子
I feel as though I'd...I'd collected a whole shelf full of bottles.
有时  那些小瓶子装着魔鬼
Sowetiwes,you know,those little bottles contain demons
会突然跑出来瞪着你
that have a way of popping out at you,
正像你要试图拚命去忘记
just as you're trying most desperately to forget.
别咬指甲了
Stop biting your nails.
但愿我是个36岁上下的女人
披一身黑缎子  戴一串珍珠项链
I wish I were a woman of 36,dressed in black satin with a atring of pearls.
如果你是这样一个人物  此刻你就不会和我在一起
You wouldn't be here with me if you were.
请你告诉我
Would you please tell me,Mr.be Winter,why you asked me to come out with you?
德温特先生  你为什么要约我出来
显然你是想要表示友好
It's obvious you want to be kind,but why do you choose me for your charity?
但为什么选择我呢
我邀你跟我一起出来是因为我想与你为伴
I asked you to come out with me because I wanted your company.
你替我抹去往昔的影子
You've blotted out the past for me more than
你的力量比灯红酒绿的蒙特卡洛要大得多
all the bright lights of Monte Carlo.
但如果你认为我只是出于好意约你或是可怜你
But if you think I just asked you out of kindness or charity,
那么你此刻就可以下车  自己寻路回去
you can leave the car now and find your own way home.
快呀  开门下车啊
Go on. Open the door and get out.
擤擤鼻涕吧
-Better blow your nose. -Thank you.
请别再叫我德温特先生
Please don't call me Mr.de Winter
我有一个令人印象非常深刻的名字
I have a very impressive array of first name.
乔治・弗特斯克・马克西米利安
George Fortescue Maximilian.
但你无需称呼我全名
You needn't bother with them all at once. My family call ma Maxim.
家里人都叫我迈克西姆
还有一件事
And another thing,
答应我  你一辈子不穿黑缎子衣服和珍珠项链
please promise me never to wear black satin or pearls,
也不假装自己是36岁
or to be 36 years old.
好的  迈克西姆
Yes Maxim.
(HUMMING)
以圣彼得爱之名  快来
EDYTUN: For the love of Pete! Come here!
你觉得如何  我女儿要结婚了
What do you think? My daughter's engaged to be married.
-真的吗  太好了  -我们必须马上启程去纽约
Oh,really? How nice!
在亚奎丹尼亚订票
We must leave for New York at once. Get reservations on the Aquitania,
我们搭12点半的火车前往瑟堡
and we'll take the 12:30 train for Cherbourg
快点  找个女仆帮忙收拾行李  我们没时间可耽误了
Hurry up and get me the maid to help with the packing.
快去啊  别磨磨蹭蹭的
We've no time to waste. Go on and don't dawdle.
请接德温特先生
Mr.de Winter,please.
他出去骑马了?
He's gone out riding?
中午才能回来?
He won't be back till noon?
请 帮我叫个门童
Give me the porter,please.
我去看看是否有东西落房间了
I'll go and see if there's anything left in my room.
德温特先生回来了吗
Has Mr.de Winter come in yet?
回来了?  请帮我接通他的电话
Oh,he has? Would you connect me,please?
我 我在找我的书  我想 已经打包了
I was looking for my book. I suppose I've packed it.
快点  车在门外等着呢
Well,come on,the car's waiting at the door.
(RINGING)
我要去留个转寄地址  如果他们找到那本书的话
I'd like to leave a forwarding address,if they happen to find that book.
请帮我接德温特先生的电话
-Would you ring Mr.de Winter,please? -Yes,madame.
是  夫人  122房间
(SPEAKS FRENCH)
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(SHOWER RUNNING)
没人接
-There isn't any answer -Thank you.
谢谢
-叫她快点  -好的  夫人
-Tell her to hurry up! -Yes,madame.
我找德温特先生
I was looking for Mr.de Winter
德温特先生刚订了早餐送去房间  小姐
Mr.de Winter just ordered breakfast in his room,mademoiselle.
请进
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
MAXIM: Come in.
你好啊  怎么了  发生什么事了
Hello. What are you doing here?
我是来道别的  我们就要走了
Anything the matter?
I've come to say goodbye. We're going away.
-你在胡说八道些什么  -是真的
What on Earth are you talking about?
我们马上要走了  我怕再也见不到你了
It's true.We’regoing now,
and I was afraid I wouldn't see you again.
她要带你去哪儿
-Where's she taking you to? -New York. I don't want to go.
纽约  可我不想去
我恨纽约之行  我会很苦恼的
I shall hate it. I shall be miserable.
我去换衣服  很快就好
I'll dress in here.
I shan’t be long.
你比较喜欢哪个  纽约还是曼陀丽
Which would you prefer,New York or Menderley?
别开玩笑了  范・霍珀太太正在等着
Oh,please don’t joke about it.
我最好马上说再见
Mrs.Van Hopper’s waiting. I’d better say goodbye now.
我再重复一遍
I’ll repeat what I said.
你要跟范・霍珀太太去美国
Either you go to America with Mrs.Van Hopper,
还是跟我一起回曼陀丽
or you come home to Manderley with me.
你是说  你想雇一个秘书之类的人?
You mean you want a secretary or something?
我是要你嫁给我  你这个小傻瓜
I’m asking you to marry ma,you little fool.
请进
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
MAXIM: Come in.
是我的吗  我饿死了  一点早餐都没吃呢
Is that my food? I’m famished. I didn’t have any breakfast.
你对我的建议好像不领情啊  抱歉
My suggestion didn’t seem to go at all well. Sorry.
你不懂
Oh,but you don’t understand. It’s the...
男人可不找我这样的人结婚
-I’m not the sort of person men marry -What on Earth do you mean?
你这话究竟是什么意思
至少有一点  我不是你那个圈子里的人
I don’t belong in your sort of world,for one thing.
什么圈子
Well,what in my sort of world?
曼陀丽啊  你知道我的意思
Well,Manderley. You know what I mean.
你是不是属于那个圈子  只有我才能下判断
Well,I’m the best judge of whether you belong there or not.
当然  如果你不爱我  那就是另一回事了
Of course,if you don’t love me,that’s a different thing.
这对我的自负倒是一个很好的教训
Fine blow to my conceit,that’s all.
我爱你  非常非常爱
I do love you. I love you most dreadfully.
我整个早上都在哭  因为我以为再也见不到你了
I’ve been crying all morning because I thought I’d never see you again.
愿上帝保佑你
Bless you for that.
某天我会使你想起此事  你不会相信我
If I remind you of this one day and you won't believe me.
很遗憾你必须长大
It’s a pity you have to grow up.
现在搞定了  你可以帮我倒杯咖啡了
Well,now that’s settled. You way pour me out some coffee.
加两块糖跟一些牛奶  谢谢
Two lumps of sugar and some milk,please. Same with my tea,don’t forget.
茶也一样  别忘了
谁去跟范・霍珀夫人谈这件事儿  你去还是我去
Who is going to break the news to Mrs.Van Hopper? Shall you or should I?
你去跟她说  她一定会气个半死
You tell her.She’ll be so angry.
她房间电话多少
What’s the number of her room?
她不在房间  她在楼下车里
She’s not there. She’s downstairs in the car.
喂  请帮我接前台
Hello. Give me the desk,please.
喂  你会看到范・霍珀太太在外面车里等着
Hello.You’ll find Mrs.Van Hopper waiting outside in her car.
你去叫她  并代我向她致意
Would you ask her,with my compliments,
问她是否愿意来我房间
if she’d very kindly come up and see me is my room?
是的  到我房间
Yes,is my room.
德温特先生说请你到他房间
Mr.de Winter says please for you to come up to his room.
德温特先生?  乐意之极
Mr. de Winter?
Why,certainly.
这并不是你理想中的求婚  是吗
(MAXIM CHUCKLING)
This isn’t at all your idea of a proposal.is it?
应该在温室中
It should be is a conservatory,
你穿着白色连衣裙  手里拿着一束红玫瑰
you in a white frock,with a red rose in your hand,
并且在远处有人拉着小提琴
and a violin playing in the distance,
我该站在棕树后面像你求爱
and I should be making violent love to you behind a palm tree.
亲爱的小可怜  不用担心
Poor darling. Never mind.
我不担心
I don’t mind.
别担心 你无需开口
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Don’t worry.Don’t worry.You won’t have to say a word.
很高兴你叫我来  德温特先生
I’m so glad you called me,Mr.de winter
我正赶着离开  没告诉你真太不礼貌了
I was making a hasty departure.
今早有个电报发过来说
It was so rude of me not to let you know.
我女儿要结婚了
But a cable came this morning announcing that my daughter
那太巧了  范・霍珀太太
in engaged to be married.
That’s rather a coincidence,Mrs.Van Hopper.
我叫您来这儿  正是为了告诉您我订婚的事
I asked you up here in order to tell you of my engagement.
你不会是开玩笑吧  太棒了
You don’t mean it. How perfectly wonderful.
多么浪漫啊  谁是那位幸运的姑娘
How romantic. Who is the lucky lady?
我为以如此唐突的方式夺走您的同伴而道歉
I apologize for depriving you of your companion in this adrupt way.
我真希望不会为您造成太大的不便
I do hope it won’t inconvenience you too greatly.
这些都是什么时候发生的事
When did all this happen?
就刚才  范・霍珀太太  就在几分钟之前
Just now,Mrs.Van Hopper. Just a few minutes ago.
我简直不敢相信
I simply can’t believe it.
我想我应该因你没跟我
And I suppose I ought to scold you
透露半点风声而责怪你
for not having breathed a word of all of this to me.
我在想什么呀
What am I thinking of?
我该恭喜祝福你们俩
I should give you both my congratulations and my blessings.
我真替你们俩开心  什么时候在哪里举行婚礼
I’m very happy for you both.
-在这儿  越快越好  -闪电结婚啊
-When and where is the wedding to be? -Here,as soon as possible.
好极了  我可以推迟船期1周
A whirlwind romance. Splendid! I can easily postpone my sailing for a week.
这可怜的孩子没有母亲
This poor child has no mother,
所以我该承担所有安排事物的责任
so I shall take responsibility for all the arrangements.
嫁妆  接待等等
Trousseau,reception and everythinp,and I'll give the bride away.
并由我将新娘交给新郎  但我们的行李
But our luggage.
下去告诉门僮把所有东西都从车里搬出来
Go down and tell the porter to take everything out of the car.
等等
Just a minute.We’re most grateful,Mrs.Van Hopper,
我们不胜感激  但我想我们俩
都比较喜欢低调处理此事
but I think we’d both prefer to have it all as quiet as posaible.
-我不能让您改船期  -但是
And I couldn't possibly allow you to change your sailing plans.
不 亲爱的  我下去看看  把你的行李拿回来
―Oh,but... -No,no,no.
Dear,I’ll go down and see that your luggage in brought back.
谢谢  马克西姆
Thank you,Maxim.
那么  这事是在我生病期间发生的
So this is what’s been happening during my illness.
网球课  那才怪呢
Tennis lessons,my foot.
我猜我得颁个闪电恋爱奖给你
I suppose I’ve to hand it to you for a fast worker.
这事怎么给你办成的  静水流深啊
How did you manage it?
Still waters certainly run deep.
你说  你有没有做什么不该做的事情
Tell me,have you been doing anything you shouldn’t?
我不明白你在说些什么
好吧  没有关系
-I don’t know what you mean. -Well,never mind.
我常说英国男人的品味很怪异
I always did say that Englishmen have strange tastes.
你今后要担负曼陀丽女主人的职责
You certainly have your work cut out as mistress of Manderley.
说句老实话  亲爱的  我看你根本对付不了
To be perfectly frank with you,my dear,I can’t see you doing it.
你没有经验
You haven't the experience,
你一点也不懂做一名好夫人意味着什么
you haven’t the faintest idea what it means to be a great lady.
当然  你知道他为什么要娶你
Of course you knoe why he's marrying you,don’t you?
你不会自欺欺人地以为他爱着你吧
You haven’t flattered yourself that he’s in love with you?
实际情况是一幢空房子弄得他神经受不了
Fact is,that empty house got on his nerves to such an extent,
简直要把他逼疯
he nearly went off his head.
他只是无法继续独居
He just couldn’t go on living alone.
范・霍珀太太  你该走了  你会赶不上火车的
You’d better leave,Mrs.Van Hopper.You’ll miss your train.
德温特太太
(SCOFFS)
再见  亲爱的  祝你好运
Mrs.de Winter
Goodbye,my dear,and good luck!
(DOOR CLOSES)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
先生  你忘了拿结婚证书
Monsieur!
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
他说我忘了拿我们的结婚证书
What is he saying?
He says I’ve forgotten the proof that we’re married.
天哪
Good heavens.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
有人跟我们有同样的想法呢
Somebody else had the same idea.
-她很漂亮吧  -是的
-Isn't she sweet? -Yes.
你喜欢穿婚纱  对吧
You’d have liked a bridal veil,wouldn’t you?
或者至少
Or at least...
夫人  多少钱  全要了
(BOTH SPEAKING FRENCH)
非常感谢  夫人  谢谢
马克西姆  好美啊
Oh,Maxim,how lovely.
太美了
How perfectly lovely.
(STUTTERING)
Perfectly lovely
(CAR HONKING)
-欢迎回家  德温特先生  -谢谢  史密斯
SMITH:Welcome home,Mr.de Winter.MAXIM: Thank you,Smith.
-冷吗  亲爱的  -有一点儿
-Gold,darling? -Yes,just a little bit.
没必要害怕
There’s no need to be frightened,you know.
你只要态度真诚自然  他们肯定都会喜欢你
Just he yourself,and they’ll all adore you?
至于家务  你一点不用过问
You don’t have to worry about the house at all.
丹弗斯太太是管家  交给她就行了
Mrs. Danvers is the housekeeper Just leave it to her.
下雨了  我们最好开快点
Hello.It’s starting to rain. We’d better hurry up.
给  披上这个  盖在你头上
Here. Have this. Put it over your head.
谢谢
Thank you.
到了  那就是曼陀丽
MAXIM:That’s it.That’s Manderley.
我们到了  弗里思  大家都好吗
-Here we are. Frith everybody well? -Yes,thank you,sir.
很好  谢谢  先生  很高兴看到您回家  先生
Glad to see you home,sir.
-这位是德温特太太  弗里思  -你好
-This is Mrs.de Winter,Frith. -How do you do?
我没料到会所有人都出来迎接
I didn’t expect the whole staff to be in attendance.
丹弗斯太太嘱咐的  先生
Mrs.Danvers’orders,sir.
抱歉  不会很久的
Oh. Sorry about this. It won’t take long.
这位是丹弗斯太太
This is Mrs. Danvers.
你好
How do you do?
我已为您准备好一切
I have everything in readiness for you.
谢谢你的好意  我不需要什么
That’s very good of you. I... I didn’t expect anything.
弗里思  我们要喝点茶
-I think we’d like some tea,Frith. -Ready in the library,sir.
在藏书室里备好了  先生
过来  亲爱的
Come along,darling.
马克西姆  快进来
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Oh,Maxim,come in.
晚上好  丹弗斯太太
Oh.
晚上好  夫人
-Good evening,Mrs.Danvers. -Good evening madam.
希望爱丽丝能令您满意  夫人
-I hope Alice was satisfactory,madam. -Oh,yes,thank you,perfectly.
-满意  谢谢  很满意  -她是客厅女仆
她会照顾你  直到你的专属女佣来了为止
She’s the parlor maid.
She’ll have to look after you until your own maid arrives.
但我不需要女佣  我肯定爱丽丝会做得很好
Oh,but I haven’t a maid. I’m sure Alice will do very nicely.
恐怕那不会很久  夫人
I’m afraid that would not do for very long,madam.
作为女主人有专属女佣是很平常的
It’s usual for ladies in your position to have a personal maid.
我希望您喜欢这些房间的新装修  夫人
I hope you approve the new decoration of these rooms,madam?
我不知道已经换过了呢
Oh,I didn’t know it had been changed.
我希望没有给你们带来太多麻烦
I hope you haven't been to too much trouble.
我只是依照德温特先生的指示办事而已
I only followed out Mr.de Winter’s instructions.
之前是什么样子的
Well,what did it look like before?
各种各样的帷幕  帘子等等
It had an old paper and different hangings.
除了偶尔接待宾客  这套房间不大使用
It was never used much except for occasional visitors.
这么说  这不是他原来的卧室
Oh. Then it wasn’t Mr.de Winter’s room originally?
是的  夫人  过去他从来没用过东厢的房间
No,madam. He’s never used the east wing before.
当然  从这儿看不到海景
Of course,there’s no view of the sea from here.
西翼的房间是唯一的无敌海景房
The only good view of the sea is from the west wing.
房间很温馨  住在这儿肯定会非常舒服
The room’s very charming,and I’m sure I’ll be comfortable.
夫人  如果您有什么事  只要告诉我就行了
If there’s anything you want done,madam,you have only to tell me.
你来曼陀丽好些年了吧
I suppose you’ve been at Manderley for many years,longer than anyone else.
大概比谁待的时间都长
不  弗里思比我来得早  老爷在世的时候  他就来了
Not so long as Frith.
那时  德温特先生还是个孩子
He was here when the old gentleman was living,
是这样啊  你是在那以后才来的?
when Mr.de Winter was a boy.
Oh I see. And you didn’t come till after that?
我来时正好是头一位德温特夫人嫁过来的时候
I came here when the first Mrs.de Winter was a bride.
丹弗斯太太  我希望我们俩能互相了解  处好关系
Mrs.Danvers,I do hope we’ll be friends.
你对我得有点耐心
You must be petiest with me.
因为这样的生活对我来说完全是新的
我一定要努力适应这儿
This sort of life is new to me and I do want to make a success of it,
让德温特先生过得幸福
and make Mr.de Winter happy,
我知道一切家务安排全可交给你管
so I know I can leave all the household arrangements to you.
好的  但愿一切都能遂您的心意
Very well.I hope I shall do everything to your satisfaction,madam.
自从德温特太太去世  都是由我来管理家务
I’ve managed the house since Mrs.de Winter’s death
德温特先生从来没表示过不满意
and Mr.de Winter has never complained.
我现在要下楼了
I think I’ll go downstairs now.
通过那道门就是我告诉你的
That room in the west wing I was telling you about in there,through that door.
西厢的房间
现在不用了
It’s not used now.
那是这栋房里最漂亮的房间
It’s the most beautiful room is the house,
是唯一能穿过草坪遥看大海的房间
the only one that looks down across the lawns to the sea.
那曾是德温特夫人的卧室
It was Mrs.de Winter’s room.
-早上好  -早上好
-Good morning. -Good morning.
你是德温特太太  是吗
-Yon’re Mrs.de Winter,aren't you? -Yes.
-是的  -我叫克劳莱
My name’s Crawley.I manage the estate for Maxim.
我为马克西姆管理财产事物
很高兴见到你
Awfully glad to meet you.
害怕当马克西姆不在的时候所有事都堆到一块儿了
(CRAWLEY TITTERS)
A fearful lot of stuff piled up while Maxim was away.
是的  我肯定会这样
Yes I’m sure there must have been. I do wish I could help with some of it.
我真的希望能帮上什么忙
不  弗兰克绝不允许任何人帮他
No,no. Frank never allows anybody to help him.
他就处理像账单  房租跟税务这些鸡毛蒜皮的事
He’s like an old mother hen with his bills and rents and taxes.
走吧  弗兰克  我们必须看一下这些评估
Come on,Frank,we must go over these estimates.
我去拿文件
I’ll get my papers.
你会发现那边有很丰盛的早餐
You’ll find quantities of breakfast over there.
你必须都吃完  不然就是对厨师的不敬
But you must eat it all,or Cook will be mortally offended.
我会尽量的  马克西姆
I’ll do my best,Maxim.
我得跟弗兰克去个地方
I have to go over the place with Frank,
以确保万无一失
just to make sure that he hasn't lost any of it.
但你会好好的  对吗
You’ll be all right,won’t you? Getting acquainted with your new howe?
开始了解你的新家了吗
看看《纽约时报》  有一篇关于
Have a look at The Times. There’s a thrilling article
英格兰板球问题所在的尖锐文章
on what’s the matter with English cricket.
对了
Oh,yes...
我姐姐比阿特丽斯跟她丈夫
My sister,Beatrice,and her husband,Giles Lacy,
贾尔斯・莱斯要来吃顿中饭
have invited themselves over for lunch.
-今天吗  -是的
-Today? -Yes.
我猜想大姐迫不及待要来看你
I suppose the old girl can’t wait to look you over.
你会发现她为人很直
You’ll find her very direct.
她如果对你没有什么好感  就会当着你的面说出来
If she doesn’t like you,she’ll probably tell you so to your face.
别担心  亲爱的  我会及时回来保护你的
Don’t worry,darling,I’ll be back in time to protect you from her.
-再见  亲爱的  -再见  马克西姆
-Goodbye,darling. -Goodbye,Maxim.
-再见  -再见
-Goodbye. -Goodbye.
-早上好  夫人  -早上好  弗里思
-Good morning,madam. -Good morning,Frith.
有什么需要我为您效劳的吗  夫人
Isn’t there anything I could get for you,madam?
不用  谢谢  弗里思  我真的不是很饿
No,thank you,Frith. I’m really not very hungry.
谢谢
Thank you.
-报纸  夫人  -对的  谢谢  弗里思
-The paper,madam. -Oh,yes. Thank you,Frith.
-夫人  -脚滑了一下
I slipped.
谢谢  弗里思
Thank you,Frith.
-好大呀  -是的  夫人  曼陀丽是个很大的地方
-It’s big,isn’t it? -Yes,madam,Manderley is a big place.
过去这个曾是宴会厅
This was the banquet hall is the old days.
这仍旧用以大庆  像是大的宴会或是舞会
It’s still used on great occasions,such as a big dinner or a ball.
是这儿的传统  一周一次
And the public is admitted here,you know,once a week.
真好
That’s nice.
太太  您要什么
藏书室里通常
I beg pardon,madam.
下午才生火
I’m afraid the fire is not usually lit in the library until the afternoon.
此刻晨室里已生了火
But you’ll find one in the morning room.
当然  要是您吩咐在藏书室里也生火
Of course,if you wish this fire lit now,madam...
不必  我没有这个意思
No,Frith. I wouldn’t dream of it.
德温特太太
Mrs.de Winter...
过去  德温特夫人在早餐后总在那儿
I mean,the late Mrs.de Winter
写信  打电话
always did her correspondence and telephoning in the morning room,
谢谢  弗里思
after breakfast.
Thank you,Frith.
怎么了  夫人
Is anything wrong,madam?
没有  晨室怎么走
Oh,no. Which way is the morning room?
-那边左边那扇门  -好  谢谢
Oh,it’s that door there,on the left.
Oh,yes,thank you.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
德温特太太?  恐怕您弄错了吧
Mrs.de Winter? Oh,I’m afraid you’ve made a mistake.
德温特太太去世已经一年多了
Mrs.de Winter’s been dead for ever a year.
我是说
Oh,I mean...
那是内线电话  夫人
Oh.
可能园丁长想要请示
That was the house telephone,madam.
Probably the head gardener wishing instruction.
你要见我吗  丹弗斯太太
Did you want to see me,Mrs.Danvers?
德温特先生通知我  他姐姐莱斯太太
Mr.de Winter informed me that his sister,Mrs.Lacy,and Major Lacy
跟莱斯少校会来用午餐
are expected for luncheon.
我想知道今天的菜单是不是合意
I’d like to know if you approve of the menu.
挺合适的  确实好极了
Oh ,well I’m sure it’s very suitable,very nice indeed.
请您看一下  在调味两字的边上我留出了空白
You will notice,madam,that I’ve left a blank space for the sauce.
过去德温特夫人非常讲究调味汁
Mrs.de Winter was most particular about sauces.
我看德温特夫人喜欢什么  你们就看着办好了
Let's have whatever you think that Mrs.de Winter would have ordered.
谢谢  夫人
Thank you,madam.
你的信什么时候写完  罗伯特会拿去邮局寄
When you’ve finished your letters,Robert will take them to the post.
我的 我的信?
My... My letters?
是的  当然  谢谢  丹弗斯太太
Oh,yes,of course. Thank you,Mrs.Danvers.
-你好  弗里思  -早上好  莱斯太太
-BEATRICE: How are you,Frith? -Good morning,Mrs.Lacy.
-德温特先生在哪儿  -跟克劳莱先生去农场了
Where’s Mr.de Winter?
FRICH: I believe he went down to the farm with Mr.Crawley.
真讨厌  我们来的时候  他老是不在
BEATRICE: How tiresome of him not to be bere when we arrive,and how typical.
(WHINING)
我必须说  老丹弗斯把这个房子管理得挺不错
BEATRICE: I must say old Danvers keeps the house looking lovely.
她肯定跟丽贝卡学了花艺技巧
She’s certainly learned that trick of arranging flowers from Rebecca.
我想知道现在她有多喜欢它
GIlES: I wonder how she likes it now,
被一个交际花不断差遣
being ordered about by an ex-chorus girl.
你到底从哪儿得知她是以前是个交际花啊
BEATRICE: Now,where on Earth did you get the idea
他在法国南部搭上她的  不是吗
she’s an ex-chorus girl?
He picked her up in the South of France,didn’t he?
-是又怎样  -我的意思是说  那就是了
What if he did?
Well,I mean to say,there you are.
您好  我是迈克西姆的太太
How do you do?I’m Maxim’s wife.
你好啊
How do you do?
你跟我猜想的完全不同
Well I must say you’re quite different from what I expected.
别说傻话了  她跟我和你讲的完全一样
Don’t be so silly. She’s exactly what I told you she’d be.
-觉得曼陀丽怎么样  -很漂亮  不是吗
Well,how do you like Manderley?
跟丹弗斯太太相处得怎么样
It’s very beautiful,isn’t it?
And how do you get along with Mrs.Danvers?
以前我从未见过像她那样的人
Well. I...
I’ve never met anyone quite like her before.
你是说她使你害怕?  她那副尊容可实在上不了油画
You mean,she scares you.
She’s not exactly an oil painting,is she?
贾尔斯  你话有点多啊  到别处去吧
Giles,you’re very much in tha way here. Go somewhere else.
我去找迈克西姆  可以吗
Well,I'll try and find Maxim,shall I?
贾尔斯
Giles.
我无意说丹弗斯太太坏话
I didn’t mean to say anything against Mrs.Danvers.
你没必要怕她
Oh,there’s no need for you to be frightened of her,
但我应该比她好相处
but I shouldn’t have any more to do with her than you can help.
-我们可以坐下吗  -当然  请坐
-Shall we sit down? -Yes. Yes,please.
她起初一定会疯狂嫉妒
You see,she’s bound to be insanely jealous at first
并且她肯定对你极度不满
and she must resent you bitterly.
-为什么  -你不知道吗
But why should she?
我还以为迈克西姆肯定跟你说起过
Don’t you know?
I should have thought Maxim would have told you.
她对丽贝卡崇拜得五体投地
She simply adored Rebecca.
-你好  罗伯特  -很好  谢谢  夫人
-How are you,Robert? -Quite well,thank you,madam.
-牙还疼吗  -还会疼呢  夫人
-Still having trouble with your teeth? -Unfortunately,you,madam.
该把它们都拔掉  都拔掉  讨厌的东西  牙齿
You must have them out,all of them.
-谢谢  夫人  -好大一盘啊
-Wretched nuisances,teeth. -Thank you,madam.
-你会打猎吗  -不会  恐怕我连骑马都不会
What a plateful.
Do you hunt?
No,I don’t. I’m afraid I don’t even ride.
一定要在这儿骑马  我们都会
Yon have to ride down here,we all do.
你骑哪种  横座马鞍还是跨骑?
Which do you ride,sidesaddle or astride?
对了  我忘了  你不会骑马
Well,of course,I forgot. You don’t,do you?
你一定得学啊  这儿没什么事可做
You must. Nothing else to do around here.
迈克西姆  你什么时候要再在这儿办派对  像以往一样
Maxim,when are you going to have parties here again,like the old days?
-我还没想过呢  -但大家都期待看你和
I haven’t thought about it.
诗啊  我肯定他们很期待
-But everyone’s dying to see you and... -Yes,I bet they are.
你怎么不再举办化妆舞会了呢
Why don’t you have the masquerade ball again this summer?
亲爱的  你喜欢跳舞吗
My dear,are you fond of dancing?
喜欢  但我跳得不好
I love it,but I’m not very good at it.
-你会跳伦巴吗  -我没跳过呢
Do you rumba?
你一定要向我请教
-Never tried. -You must teach me.
我说  老弟  我在尝试获悉你老婆到底会做什么
Actually,I’m trying to find out exactly what your wife does do.
她会点素描
She sketches a little.
素描  我希望不是什么现代主义的玩意
Sketches.
画一个倒置灯罩的画像
Not this modern stuff,I hope,you know,portrait of a lampshade upside down
来表现痛苦中的灵魂
to represent a soul in torment.
-会开船吗  -不会
Don’t sail,do you?
谢天谢地  幸亏你不会
No,I don’t.
Thank goodness for that.
Huh?
你很爱迈克西姆  对吗
You’re very much in love with Maxim,aren’t you?
我看得出来
Yes,I can see you are.
别介意我那么说  我觉得你的头发得好好弄一弄
Don’t mind my saying so,but why don’t you do something about your hair?
为什么不剪一下  或者拢到耳朵后面去
Whydon’tyon days it oat or nwnng it band dndind ynnrsara’?
不行 不行  这样更糟  迈克西姆怎么说
Oh,no,that’s worse.
-他喜欢这样吗  -他从来没提起过
What does Maxim say about it? Does he like it like that?
Well,he never mentions it.
那就别听我的
Oh. well,don’t go by me.
从你的穿着看  你对服饰打扮压根不在乎
I can see by the way you dress you don’t care a hoot how you look.
真奇怪  迈克西姆怎么一点儿不在乎呢
But I wonder Maxim hasn’t been at you. He’s so particular about clothes.
他对穿着总是很挑剔的
我看他甚至根本不注意我的穿戴
I don’t think he ever notices what I wear.
那么说来  他的性格大概变了
Oh. He must have changed a lot,then.
你无需担心老迈克西姆跟他的心情
You mustn’t worry about old Maxim and his moods.
没人知道他脑袋瓜里在想什么
One never knows what goes on in that quiet mind of his.
他经常大发脾气  当他发脾气的时候
Often,he gets into a terrible rage,and when he does...
但我觉得他不会对你发脾气
(WHISTLES)
I don’t suppose he’ll lose his temper with you?
你是个沉静的小乖乖
You seem such a placid little thing.
快走  老太婆  3点我们要去看高尔夫球赛
Come on,old girl.We’ve got to go on the first ten at 3:00.
行了  我来了
All right,I’m coming.
再见  迈克西姆老弟
GILES: Well,goodbye,Maxim,old boy.
再见  贾尔斯  感谢你的光临  老兄
Goodbye,Giles. Thanks for coming,old boy.
在建  亲爱的  原谅我问了你那么多无礼的问题
Goodbye,my dear. Forgive me for asking you so many rude questions.
我们俩真的希望你们会很幸福
We both really hope yon’ll be very happy.
谢谢  比阿特丽斯  非常感谢
Thank you,Beatrice,thank you very much.
我得恭喜你迈克西姆现在看起来很开心
And I must congratulate you upon the way Maxim looks.
去年这个时候我们都很担心他
We were very worried about him this time last year.
但另一方面  当然  你知道整件事情
But then of course,you know the whole story
-再见  比阿特丽斯  亲爱的  -再见  老弟
-MAXIM: Goodbye,Beatrice. -Goodbye,old boy.
-再见  -再见
-Goodbye. -Goodbye.
谢天谢地他们走了  现在我们可以去散散步了
Well,thank heavens they’ve gone.
Now we can have a walk about the place.
看来我们要变落汤鸡了
Looks as though we might have a shower.but you won’t mind that,will you?
但你不会介意吧
No,but wait a minute. I’ll go upstairs and get a coat.
不介意  但我要去拿件外套
There’s a heap of mackintoshes in the flower room. Robert?
花房里一大堆胶布雨衣
罗伯特  快跑去花房拿件外套
Run and get a coat from the flower room for Mrs.de Winter,will you?
给德温特太太  好吗
What do you think of Beatrice?
-你觉得比阿特丽斯怎么样  -我很喜欢她
Oh,I liked her very much,but she kept saying
她说我同她原先想像的不大一样
that I was quite different from what she expected.
她想像中的你究竟是什么样子
What the devil did she expect?
Oh,someone smarter and more sophisticated,I’m afraid.
我想  她以为我一定既漂亮又老练
你喜欢我头发得样子吗
Do you like my hair?
你的头发?  当然了  怎么会想到这上头的
Your hair? Yes,of course I do. What’s the matter with it?
没什么  我只不过随口问问
Oh,I don’t know. I just wondered.
你这人真怪
How funny you are.
-谢谢  -必须穿上吗
Thank you.
是  当然 不能老像个小孩似的要人关心
-Do I have to put it on? -Yes,certainly,certainly,certainly.
You can’t be too careful with children.
快来  杰斯珀  去溜溜腿  跑掉点脂肪
Come on,Jasper.Come and take some of that fat off.
杰斯珀  这边  不是那边
Jasper! Here. Hot that way! Come here!
过来这边
(MAXIM WHISTLES)
那通向哪儿
Where does that lead to?
我们过去用来停船的小海湾
Oh,it leads to a little cove where we used to keep a boat.
那我们去那儿吧
Oh.let’s go down there.
不  那是个非常无聊的地方  无趣的绵延沙滩
Well,no.It’s a perfectly dull,uninteresting stretch of sand,
就像其它沙滩一样
-just like any other. -Oh,please.
-求你了  -好吧
Well,all right.We’ll walk down and take a look if you really want to.
如果你真想去的话  那我们就下去看看
(BARKING)
是杰斯珀  那儿肯定有什么不对劲  他可能受伤了
That’s Jasper.There must be something wrong.
-不  他没事  -我最好还是过去看看吧
-Perhaps he’s hurt himself. -No,he’s all right,leave him alone.
Don’t you think I’d better go and see?
别担心  他不会受伤的
Don’t bother about him,I tell you,he can't come to any harm.
他会自己回来的
He’ll find his own way back!
杰斯珀  杰斯珀
Jasper!Jasper?
你在这儿啊
Oh,there you are.
(BARKING)
你在那儿干吗  杰斯珀  快走  快回家
What do you want in there,Jasper? Come on. Come on home.Let’s go home.
我们回家吧  杰斯珀  杰斯
Jasper...
我不知道有人住
Oh.
I didn’t know that there was anybody...
我认识这条狗  他来自那栋房子
I know that dog.
He comes from the house.
他不是你的狗
He ain’t yours.
对  他是德温特先生的狗
No.He’s Mr.de Winter’s dog.
你有什么东西可以拴住他的吗
Have you anything I could tie him with?
来  杰斯珀
Come on,Jasper.
你不会告诉别人在这儿看到过我吧
You won’t tell anyone you saw me in there,will you?
这房子难道不是你的吗
Don’t you belong on the estate?
我什么也没干  我只是在收拾我的贝壳
I weren’t doing nothing.
I was just putting me shells away.
她被大海带走了  是吗
She’s gone in the sea,ain’t she?
她再也不会回来了
She’ll never come back no more.
对  她永远不会回来了  快走  杰斯珀
No.She’ll never come back.
Come on,Jasper.
迈克西姆  怎么了
Maxim!What’s the matter?
迈克西姆
Maxim!
对不起我去了那么久  我找了根绳子拴住杰斯珀
I’m sorry I was such a time,but I had to find a rope for Jasper.
快点  杰斯珀  天哪
Hurry up,Jasper,for heaven’s sake.
请等等我  迈克西姆  怎么了  你看起来很生气
Please wait for me. Maxim,what is it? You look so angry.
你知道我不想你去那边  但你非要去
You know I didn’t want you to go there,but you deliberately went.
为什么不让我去
Why not? There was only a cottage down there and a strange man who...
下面只有一间小屋跟一个奇怪的男人
-你没进去那间小屋吧  -进了  门
-You didn’t go in the cottage,did yon? -Yes,the door was...
-别再去那儿了  听见了吗  -为什么
-Don’t go there again,do you hear? -Well,why not?
如果你有跟我一样的回忆
Because I hate the place. And if you had my memories,
你就不会去那里  根本连想都不会想
you wouldn’t go there or talk about it or even think about it.
怎么回事  对不起  求你了
What’s the matter? Oh,l’m sorry,please.
我们该离开  我们原不该再回曼陀丽来
We should have stayed away.
We should never have come back to Manderley.
我多蠢
Oh,what a fool I was.
我让你难过  我伤害了你
I’ve made you unhappy.Somehow,I’ve hurt you.
我无法忍受看到你这个样子
Oh,I can’t bear to see you like this
因为我太爱你了
because I love you so much.
真的?  真的?
Do you?
我把你弄哭了  原谅我
I’ve made you cry.
Forgive me.
有时我貌似会无缘无故发脾气
I sometimes seem to fly off the handle for no reason at all.
是吗
Don’t I?
走吧  我们回家  喝点茶  把所有事都忘掉
Come,we’ll go home and have some tea and forget all about it.
对  把所有事都忘掉
Yes,let’s forget all about it.
给我  让我来牵杰斯珀
Here,let me have Jasper.
-你好  请进  -请别起身  克劳莱先生
-Hello. Come in. -Oh,please don't get up,Mr.Crawley.
我只是想问你前几天说的有关教我做事的
I was just wondering if you meant what you said the other day
话是不是真的
-about showing me the run of things. -Of course I did.
-当然是真的  -你现在在干什么
What are you doing now?
通知所有佃户  庆祝
Notifying all the tenants
迈克西姆新婚
that in celebration of Maxim’s return with his bride,
本周的租金全免
this week’s rent will he free.
是迈克西姆的主意吗
Oh,is that Maxim’s idea?
Oh,yes,all the servants get an extra week’s wages,too.
是的  也将多付一周的薪水给所有的佣人
Od,he didn’t tell me.
他没告诉我
我可以帮你吗  至少我可以帮忙贴邮票
Can’t I help you? I could at least lick the stamps.
你人真好  坐下吧
Well,that’s terribly nice of you. Won’t you sit down?
好  谢谢
Yes,thank you.
前几天我去过沙滩上的小屋
I was down at the cottage on the beach the other day.
有个男人在那儿  一个怪人
There was a man there,a queer sort of person.
-杰斯珀一直冲着他叫  -那肯定是本
Jasper kept barking at him.
Oh,yes,it must have been Ben.
不好意思  他并无恶意
Excuse me.He’s quite harmless.
有时我们会给他点零活干
We give him odd jobs now and then.
那间小屋看起来破旧不堪
That cottage bay seemed to be going to rack and ruin.
为什么不去处理一下呢
Why isn't something done about it?
要是迈克西姆有意处理那屋子  我想他会对我说的
I think if Maxim wanted anything done about it,he’d tell me.
那些都是丽贝卡的东西吗
Are those all Redecca’s things down there?
是的  是的
Yes.
Yes,they are.
她用那小屋做什么
What did she use the cottage for?
那小屋以前是座船库
The boat used to be moored near there.
什么船  她的船后来怎么了
What boat? What happened to it?
她是不是开那艘船出去的时候被淹死的
Was that the boat she was sailing in when she was drowned?
是的  船翻了  她被海水冲出船舱
Yes. It capsized and sank. She was washed overboard.
单独开船出去难道她不怕吗
Wasn’t she afraid to go out like that alone?
她什么都不怕
She wasn’t afraid of anything.
他们在哪儿找到她的
Where did they find her?
大概2个月之后  大约在离海峡40英里的埃奇库姆附近
Near Edgecombe,
about 40 miles up channel about two months afterwards.
迈克西姆去认尸  那对他来说太可怕了
Maxim went up to identify her.
It was horrible for him.
是  肯定
Yes,it must have been.
克劳莱先生  请别对我的好奇心见怪
Mr.Crawley,please don’t think me morbidly curious. It isn’t that.It’s...
不是那样的  只是我感到有点处于劣势
It’s just that I feel at such a disadvantage.
一直以来  不管什么时候我见到任何人
All the time,whenever I meet anyone,Maxim’s sister or even the servants,
迈克西姆的姐姐  甚至是佣人
我知道他们都在想同一件事
I know they’re all thinking the same thing,
他们一直拿我跟丽贝卡比较
that they’re all comparing me with her with Rebecca.
你不该那么想
You mustn’t think that.
你跟迈克西姆结婚  我说不上来心里有多高兴
I can’t tell you how glad I am that you married Maxim.
他的生活因此而整个变了样
It’s going to make all the difference to his life.
依我所见  怎么说呢
From my point of view,it’s very refreshing
找到一个像你这样完全曼陀丽
to find someone like yourself,
who’s not entirely in tune,shall we say,with Manderley.
不搭的人  非常新鲜
你真好  我敢说我曾犯傻过
That’s very sweet of you.
I daresay I’ve been stupid,
我每时每刻总意识到
but every day I realize the things she had that I lack.
美丽  风趣与智慧
Beauty and wit and intelligence,
还有  所有那些东西对一个女人来说都很重要
and all the things that are so important in a woman.
但你有的那些重要的品质
You have qualities that are just as important,
要我说的话  那更重要
more important,if I may say so.
心地善良  待人诚挚
Kindliness and sincerity,
还有  如果你不见怪  谦逊端庄
and if you’ll forgive me,modesty,
对于一个做丈夫的
mean more to a husband than all the wit and beauty in the world.
比之世界上所有的机智和美貌更重要
任何人都不想活在过去里  尤其是迈克西姆
We,none of us want to live in the past,
Maxim least of all.
能否引着大家从往昔的羁缚中挣脱出来  全靠你了
It’s up to you,you know,to lead us away frow it.
我保证我再也不会提这事了
Right.
I promise you I won’t bring this up again,
可在结束谈话之前
but before we end this conversation,
你能不能如实回答我一个问题
would you answer just one more question?
如果我知道  我会尽量回答的
If it's something I’m able to answer,I’ll do my best.
告诉我  丽贝卡到底长什么样
Tell we,what was Rebecca really like?
我猜想
I suppose...
依我说  她是我有生以来见过的最美的女人
I suppose she was the most beautiful creature I ever saw.
-晚上好  迈克西姆 -好
Good evening,Maxim.
蜜月旅行的片子终于送到了
Hello. The films of the honeymoon have arrived at last.
你觉得晚餐之前我们能看看吗
Do we have time,do you think,before dinner?
你到底对自己做了些什么啊
What on Earth have you done to yourself?
没什么  只是从伦敦订了件新衣服
Oh,nothing. I just ordered a new dress frow London.
我希望你不会介意
I hope you don’t mind.
不  只是你觉得那样的东西适合你吗
Oh,no,no. Only,do you think that sort of thing’s right for you?
-它看来完全不适合你  -我以为你会喜欢的
-It doesn’t seem your type at all. -I thought you’d like it.
还有你对你的头发做什么了
And what have you done to your hair?
我明白了
Oh,I see.
亲爱的  亲爱的  对不起
Dear,oh,dear.I’m sorry.
你看起来可爱极了
You look lovely,lovely.
改变一下也很好
It’s very nice,for a change.
我们可以看照片了吗
-Shall we see these pictures? -Yes. I'd love to see them.
好  我很想看
快看  看那张
Look now,look at that.
很棒吧  亲爱的  将来我们还能再回到那儿吗
MRS.De WINTER:Wasn’t it wonderful,darling?
Can’t we go back there someday?
当然可以 瞧你  那儿
MAXIM:Yes,of course. Of course. Look at you.
当我们的子孙看到你如此可爱会非常开心的
Won’t our grandchildren be delighted when they see how lovely you were?
瞧你
MRS.DE WINTER:Oh,look at you.
(MAXIM LAUGHING)
我喜欢那张
MRS.DE WINTER:Oh,I like that.
看那张
Look at that.
-是啊  很漂亮  -记得那张吗
MAXIM: Yes,very nice.
-记得  -迈克西姆  我希望我们能永远度蜜月
-Remember that? -MAXIM:Yes.
I wish our honeymoon could have lasted forever,Maxim.
糟糕  见鬼了  等等
Dash it,look.
Hang it.
我又跟以前一样接错线了
I’ve threaded it up wrong as usual or something.
弗里思  什么事
Yes,Frith. What is it?
打扰一下  先生  我可以跟您谈件事吗
Excuse me,sir. May I have a word with you?
好  说吧
Yes. Come in.
事关于罗伯特的事  先生
It’s about Robert,sir
他和丹弗斯太太之间闹了点别扭
There’s been a slight unpleasantness between him and Mrs.Danvers.
-天哪  -罗伯特心里很不好受
Oh. dear.
-Robert is very upset. -This is trouble.
真麻烦  什么事
What is it?
丹弗斯太太职责罗伯特
It appears that Mrs.Danvers has accused Robert of stealing a valuable ornament
私藏了晨室里一件值钱的摆设
from the morning room.
罗伯特矢口否认干过这样的事
Robert denies the accusation most emphatically,sir.
-究竟是哪件小摆设  -是那尊爱神瓷塑  先生
-What was the thing,anyway? -China cupid,sir.
天哪  那可是我们家的意见宝贝  是吗
Oh,dear.That’s one of our treasures,isn’t it?
告诉丹弗斯太太
Well,tell Mrs. Danvers to get to the bottom of it somehow.
想方设法弄清事实  我肯定不是罗伯特干的
-Tell her I’m sure it wasn’t Robert. -Very good,sir.
太好了  先生
Why do they come to me with these things?That’s your job,sweetheart.
他们干吗连这种事都来找我  这种事该由你管  亲爱的
迈克西姆  我早想告诉你  可是 可是我却忘了
Maxim,I wanted to tell you,but I forgot.
-其实是我打碎了爱神瓷塑  -你打碎的?
The fact is,I broke the china cupid.
You broke it?
当你刚才在弗里思面前干吗不这么说呢
Now,why on Earth didn’t you say something about it when Frith was here?
我也不知道  我不想这么做
I don’t know. I didn’t like to.
我怕他会拿我当傻瓜看
I was afraid he’d think me a fool.
这下子他才真会拿你当大傻瓜看呢
He’ll think you much more of a fool now.
现在你可得把事情向他和丹弗斯太太讲清楚
You’ll have to explain to him and Mrs.Danvers.
-不  你去解释  我上楼去  -别像个小傻瓜似的
Oh,no,Maxim. You do it.I’ll go upstairs.
Don’t be such a littla idiot,darling.
大家会认为你怕他们
Anybody would think you were afraid of them.
完全是一场误会  丹弗斯太太
MAXIM:It’s all a mistake,Mrs.Danvers.
看来是德温特太太自己把瓷塑打碎了
Apparently,Mrs.be Winter broke the cupid herself
后来压根把这事给忘了
end forgot to say anything about it.
非常抱歉  没想到给罗伯特惹了麻烦
I’m so sorry. I never thought that I’d get Robert into trouble.
那摆设还能修补一下吗  夫人
Is it possible to repair the ornament,madam?
怕不行了　已经摔得粉碎
No,I’m afraid it isn’t. It smashed into pieces.
你怎么处理那些碎片的
What did you do with the pieces?
我把它们放进写字桌的抽屉里面了
Well,I put them at the back of one of the drawers in the writing desk.
瞧德温特夫人那模样
Well,it looks as though Mrs.de Winter was afraid
好像你会把她送进监牢似的  丹弗斯太太  对不
you were going to put her in prison,doesn’t it,Mrs. Danvers?
找出那些碎片
Well,never mind. Do what you can to find the pieces.
看看能否修好  并且告诉罗伯特擦干眼泪
See if they can be mended,and above all,tell Robert to dry his tears.
我当然要向罗伯特赔个不是
I shall apologize to Robert,of course. Perhaps if such a thing happens again,
要是以后再发生这样的事
Mrs.de Winter will tell me personally.
德温特夫人是不是可以亲口向我讲明
MAXIM:Yes,yes,all right. Thank you,Mrs.Danvers.
好了  谢谢  丹弗斯太太
我猜想片段都会完好  我也不知道
Well,I suppose that clip will hold all right. I don’t know.
亲爱的  太抱歉了  我真是粗心大意
MRS.DE WINTER:I’m awfully sorry darling.It was very careless of me.
丹弗斯太太肯定要对我大发雷霆
-Mrs.Danvers must be furious with me. -Hang Mrs.Danvers.
别管丹弗斯太太  你到底干吗要怕她啊
Why on Earth should you be frightened of her?
你的举动哪像个女主人
You behave more like an upstairs maid or something,
倒像家里的丫头呢
-not the mistress of the house at all. -Yes. I know I do.
我知道  但我感到很不自在
But I feel so uncomfortable.
每天我都竭尽全力  但上上下下的人打量着我
I try my best every day,but it’s very difficult with people looking me
就像我是一头得奖的良种母牛
up and down as if I were a prize cow.
就算这样  那又何妨
What does it matter if they do? You must remember
你必须记住  唯有曼陀丽发生的事
that life at Manderley is the only thing that interests anybody down here.
才能引起人们的兴趣
那我一定使他们大失所望了
What a slap in the aye I must have been to them,then.
你大概是因为这个缘故才跟我结婚的吧
I suppose that’s why you married me,
你知道我这个人呆板无趣  不爱讲话  又没见过世面
because you knew I was dull and gauche and inexperienced,
所以这儿的人就不屑对我蜚短流长了
and there’d never be any gossip about me.
蜚短流长?  你这话时什么意思
Gossip?What do you mean?
我 我也不知道  我这话没别的意思
I don’t know. I just said it for something to say.
你干吗要折服模样
Don’t look at me like that. Maxim.
迈克西姆  怎么了  我说什么了
What’s the matter? What have I said?
说这些话  可不怎么悦耳动听  是吗
Wasn’t a very attractive thing to say,was it?
是的  既唐突  又叫人讨厌
No.It was rude,hateful.
我怀疑自己娶你  是不是干了件极其自私的事
I wonder if I did a very selfish thing in marrying you.
你这话是什么意思
How do you mean?
我对你可不是个好伴侣  是吗
I’m not much of a companion to you,am I?
你并没有得到很多乐趣  是吗
You don’t get much fun,do you?
你应该嫁给一个跟你年龄相仿的小伙子
You ought to have married a boy,someone of your own age.
麦克斯曼  你干吗这么讲  我们当然是终生伴侣
Maxim,why do you say this? Of course we’re companions.
是吗  我可不敢说
Ars we? I don't know.
我这个人恐怕很难相处
-I’m very difficult to live with. -No,you’re not difficult.
不  一点也不难相处
You’re easy,very easy.
我们的婚姻是美满的  是天赐良缘
Our marriage is a success,isn’t it,a great success?
我们很快活  是吧  非常非常快活
We’re happy,aren’t we? Terribly happy?
如果你认为我们不开心
If you don’t think we are happy,
我并不希望你言不由衷
it would be much better if you didn’t pretend.
我会离开的
I’ll go away.
你为什么不回答我
Why don’t you answer me?
叫我怎么回答你呢  连我自己也搞不清楚
How can I answer you
when I don’t know the answer myself?
如果你说我们是快活的  那就别再往下说了
If you say we’re happy,let’s leave it at that.
我对幸福之事一无所知
Happiness is something I know nothing about.
看  那张
Oh,look.There’s the one when I left the camera
我把相机放在三脚架上的时候拍的  记得吗
running on the tripod,remember?
(INAUDIBLE)
鉴于庄园事务赴宴伦敦
我会在夜晚前赶回来
这没有我的短暂假日应该也很闲适  迈克西姆
不好意思  夫人  有什么我能为您效劳的吗
Pardon me,madam. Is there anything I can do for you?
没事  希尔达  非常感谢
I’m all right,Hilda. Thank you very much.
我马上去拿三明治  夫人
I’ll bring the sandwiches immediately,madam.
-希尔达  -是的  夫人
-Hilda. -Yes,madam?
西厢没有人再住过了  是吗
The west wing. Nobody ever uses it anymore,do they?
没有  夫人  自从德温特太太死后就没人住了
No,madam. Not since the death of Mrs.de Winter.
(DOOR OPENING)
(DOOR CLOSING)
过来  杰克先生  否则有人会看到你的
MRS.DANVERS:Come along,Mr.Jack,or someone may see you.
丹尼  老女妖  很高兴再次见到你
FAVELL:Well,Danny old harpy it’s been good to see you again.
得知所有消息简直令我窒息
I’ve been simply breathless to pick up all the news.
杰克先生  我认为您不该来这里
(BARKING)
MRS.DANVERS: I really don’t think it’s wise for you to come here,Mr.Jack.
-杰斯珀  过来  -胡说  就像回家一样
(SOFTLY)Jasper,come here.
FAVELL: Oh,nonsense,nonsense. It’s just like coming back home.
-轻一点  杰克先生  -我得小心别惊动了灰姑娘
MRS. DANVERS: Quiet,Mr.Jack.
FAVELL:Yes.We must be careful not to shock Cinderella,mustn’t we?
她在晨室
MRS.DANVERS: She’s in the morning room.
如果你从花园的门离开  她不会看到你的
If you leave through the garden door,she won’t see you.
我感觉有点像穷亲戚
FAVELL:I must say,I feel a little like the poor relation,
从后门偷偷离开
sneaking around through back doors.
-再见  丹尼  -再见  杰克先生  小心点
Well,toodle-oo,Danny
MRS.DANVERS: Goodbye,Mr.Jack,and please be careful.
(DOOR CLOSING)
杰斯珀  别出声
(WHINING)
Jasper,be quiet.
在找我吗  我没吓着你吧
FAVELL: Looking for me?
-I didn’t make you jump,did I? -No.
没有  当然没有  我根本不认识你
Of course not. I didn’t quite know who it was.
很高兴见到我吧  老伙计
Yes.You’re pleased to see me,aren’t you,old boy?
很高兴这个家有人欢迎我回到曼陀丽
I’m glad there’s someone in the family to welcome me back to Manderley.
亲爱的迈克斯老兄好吗
And how is dear old Max?
很好  谢谢
Very well,thank you.
我听说他去伦敦了  留下他的小新娘独守空闺
I hear he went up to London,left his little bride all alone.
这太糟糕了
It’s too bad.
他难道不怕会有人来把你抢走?
Isn't he rather afraid that somebody might come down and carry you off?
丹尼  你百般提防  结果还是枉费心机
Danny,all your precautions were in vain.
屋子的女主人就躲在门背后呢
The mistress of the house was hiding behind the door.
怎么不向新娘介绍我
Oh. What about presenting me to the bride?
-这位是费弗尔先生  夫人  -你好
This is Mr.Favell.madam.
How do you do?
你好
请留在这儿用茶点吧
-Won’t you have some tea or something? -Now,isn’t that a charming invitation?
这样盛情相邀  岂不让人心动
请我留下用茶点  丹尼  我还真想留下来呢
I’ve been asked to tea,Danny,and I’ve a good mind to accept.
也许你是对的
Oh,well,perhaps you're right. Pity,just when we were getting on so nicely.
可惜了  我们刚相处地很好
我们不可以带坏小新娘  对吧  杰斯珀
We mustn’t lead the young bride astray must me,Jasper?
再见  很高兴见到你
Goodbye.It’s been fun meeting you.
顺便说一下
Oh,and by the way,it would be very decent of you if you didn’t mention
要是你不在迈克斯面前提起我来过的事儿
那就太够朋友了
this little visit to your revered husband.
他对我恐怕有点看法
He doesn’t exactly approve of me.
-好的  -你可真够朋友
-Very well. -That’s very sporting of you.
我还真希望有个结婚3个月的新娘在家里等着我呢
I wish I had a young bride of three months waiting for me at home.
我是个孤苦伶仃的光棍
I’m just a lonely old bachelor.
祝你好运
Fare thee well.
我知道刚介绍错了
Oh,and I know what was wrong with that introduction.
丹尼没告诉你吧  我是丽贝卡喜爱的堂兄
Danny didn’t tell you,did she?
I am Rebecca’s favorite cousin.
再见
Toodle-oo!
(WINDOW SLAMMING)
太太  出了什么事
Do you wish anything,madam?
我没想到会在这儿看到你  丹弗斯太太
I didn’t expect to see you,Mrs.Danvers.
我看到一扇窗没关
I noticed that a window wasn’t cloned and I came up to see
所以我上来看看是不是能把它关严实
您何必对我说窗子是开着的呢
-if I could fasten it. -Why did you say that?
我离开屋子前就把窗关上了
I closed it before I left the room. You opened it yourself,didn’t you?
是您自己开的窗  对吗
你一直想看看这间房  不是吗  夫人
You’ve always wanted to see this room,haven’t you,madam?
您干吗以前不叫我领您来看呢
Why did you never ask me to show it to you?
我每天都准备陪您上这儿来
I was ready to show it to you every day.
这是个可爱的房间  是吗
It’s a lovely room,isn’t it?
您从来没有见过这么可爱的房间吧
Loveliest room you’ve ever seen.
一切都照德温特太太喜欢的摆放着
Everything is kept just as Mrs. de Winter liked it.
自那晚以来所有东西都没变过
Nothing has been altered since that last night.
来  我带您参观她的衣帽间
Come.I’ll show you her dressing room.
我把她所有的衣服都放在这里
Thin is where I keep all her clothes.
你想看  不是吗
You would like to see them,wouldn’t you?
感受一下
Feel this.
那是德温特先生送给她的圣诞礼物
It was a Christmas present from Mr.de Winter.
他总是送她贵重的礼物  整年都是
He was always giving her expensive gifts,the whole year round.
我把她的内衣放在这边
I keep her underwear on this side.
它们是圣克莱儿修道院的修女们专门为她做的
They were made specially for her by the nuns in the Convent of St.Claire.
我过去一直会等她回来  不管多晚
I always used to wait up for her no matter how late.
有时她跟德・维特先生直到黎明时分才回来
Sometimes she and Mr.de Winter didn’t come home until dawn.
她宽衣的时候  会告诉我有关她所去的派对的事
While she was undressing,she’d tell me about the party she’d been to.
她认识的所有相关人员  还有所有爱她的人
She knew everyone that mattered.
Everyone loved her.
当她洗好澡的时候
When she finished her bath,
会走进卧室  然后走向梳妆台
she’d go into the bedroom and go over to the dressing table.
你动过她的梳子  是吗
Oh,you’ve moved her brush,haven’t you? There.That's better.
在这儿  好多了  就像她一直摆放的那样
她会说  "快点  丹尼  梳头发"
Just as she always laid it down.
“Come on,Danny. Hair drill,” she would say.
我像这样站在她身后  每次梳20分钟
And I’d stand behind her like this and brush away for 20 minutes at a time.
然后她会说
And then she would say,“Good night,Danny,”
"晚安  丹尼"  然后她就上床休息
and step into her bed.
我亲手为她绣的这个衣套
I embroidered this case for her myself,and I keep it here always.
我一直把它放在这儿
你有见过如此精美的东西吗
Did you ever see anything so delicate?
瞧  你可以透过它看到我的手
Look. You can see my hand through it.
你不会以为她已经离开很久了吧
You wouldn’t think she’d been gone so long,would you?
有时我沿着这条过道走着走着
Sometimes when I walk along the corridor,
简直觉得她就跟在我身后
I fancy I hear her just behind me.
听得见她那急促而又轻快的脚步声  我绝不会搞错
That quick light step. I couldn't mistake it anywhere.
不仅是在这个房间  这栋房的所有房间都一样
Not only in this room,it’s in all the rooms in the house.
此刻我几乎也能听到
I can almost hear it now.
你相信死去的人会回来看活着的人吗
Do you think the dead come back and watch the living?
不  我不相信
No.I don’t believe it.
有时我真怀疑  她是不是悄悄回到了曼陀丽
Sometimes I wonder if she doesn’t come back here to Manderley,
注视着您和德温特先生的一举一动呢
and watch you and Mr.de Winter together.
你看起来很累  何不待在这儿休息一会
You look tired.
Why don’t you stay here a while and rest?
听听大海的声音?
And listen to the sea.
非常平静
So soothing.
听
Listen to it.
Listen.
听大海的声音
Listen to the sea.
告诉丹弗斯太太我要马上见她
Tell Mrs.Danvers I wish to see her immediately.
德温特夫妇诚邀杰克・费弗尔先生至曼陀丽庄园
丽贝卡  我会在那儿等你  --杰克
您叫我吗  夫人
You sent for me,madam?
是的  丹弗斯太太
Yes,Mrs.Danvers.
我要你把这些东西都扔掉
I want you to get rid of all these things.
这些是德温特太太的东西
-These are Mrs.de Winter's things. -I am Mrs.de Winter now.
现在我才是德温特太太
好  我会照您的指示做的
Very well.I’ll give the instructions.
(CAR HONKING)
请等一下
Just a moment,please.
丹弗斯太太  我不会告诉德温维特先生有关
Mrs.Danvers,I intend to say nothing to Mr.de Winter
费弗尔先生来访的事
about Mr.Favell’s visit.
事实上  我宁愿忘记一切今天下午所发生的一切
In fact,I prefer to forget everything that happened this afternoon.
迈克西姆  迈克西姆  一整天没看到你了
Maxim,Maxim,you’ve been gone all day.
你让我喘不过气来了
You’re choking me.
-你都做了些什么  -我在思考呢
Well,well,well,what have you been doing with yourself?
-思考什么  -进去我再告诉你
-I’ve been thinking. -What did you want to do that for?
Come in here and I’ll tell you.
亲爱的  我们可以举行一场化妆舞会吗
Darling,could we have a costume ball just as you used to?
就像以往一样
怎么会有这个想法
Now what put that into your mind?
比阿特丽斯给你洗脑了?
Has Beatrice been at you?
不  不是  但我感觉我们应该做些什么
No,no,but I feel that we ought to do something
使人们觉得曼陀丽跟以往一样
to make people feel that Manderley is just the name as it always was.
求你了  亲爱的  可以吗
Ok,please,darling,could we?
你不知道那意味着什么
You don’t know what it would mean,you know.
我要招待数百人  全国的人
You’d have to be hostess to hundreds of people,all the county.
还有很多年轻人会从伦敦赶来
And a lot of young people would come up from London,
会将房子变成夜总会那样
-and turn the house into a nightclub. -Oh,yes. But I want to. Please.
知道  但我想要嘛  求你了
我从未参加过大型派对  但我可以学习怎么做
I’ve never been to a large party,but I could learn what to do.
并且我向你保证  我不会让你丢脸的
And I promise you,you wouldn’t be ashamed of me.
好吧  如果你觉得你会喜欢的话
All right,if you think you’d enjoy it.
你最好让丹弗斯太太来帮忙  好吗
You’d better get Mrs.Danvers to help you out,won’t you?
不  不用  我不需要丹弗斯太太帮我
No,so.I don’t need Mrs.Danvers to help me. I can do it myself.
-我可以自己搞定  -好吧  我的心肝
谢谢  亲爱的  谢谢
All right,my sweet.
Thank you,darling.Thank you.
-你会打扮成什么  -我从不打扮
那是作为主人的特权
-What’ll you go as? -I never dress up.
That’s the one privilege I claim as the host.
你会打扮成什么
What will you be? Alice in Wonderland,with that ribbon around your hair?
漫游仙境里头发扎着缎带的爱丽丝吗
不告诉你  我会亲自设计我的服装
No,I won’t tell you.
给你一个终身难忘的惊喜
I’ll design a costume all by myself and give you the surprise of your life.
请进
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Come in.
罗伯特在藏书室发现了这些画稿  夫人
Robert found these sketches in the library,madam.
-你打算把它们扔掉吗  -是的  丹弗斯太太
-Did you intend throwing them away? -Yes,Mrs.Danvers,I did.
它们只是我为舞会服装画的设计稿
They were just some ideas I was sketching for my costume for the ball.
德温特先生没有给你什么建议吗
Hasn’t Mr.de Winter suggested anything?
没有  我要给他惊喜  不想让他知道
No,I want to surprise him. I don’t want him to know anything about it.
我只不过想也许
I merely thought that you might find a costume
在家族肖像画中你会找到适合你的服装
among the family portraits that would suit you.
你是说挂在楼梯边上的那些画吗  我去瞧瞧
Oh,you mean those at the top of the stairs?I’ll go and look at them.
比如这幅  也许它是为你量身订做的
This one,for instance. Might have been designed for you.
我肯定你能如法炮制一件
I’m sure you could have it copied.
我听德温特先生讲过
I’ve heard Mr.de Winter say that this is his favorite of all the paintings.
这幅是所有油画里他最喜欢的一幅
这位是卡洛琳・德温特夫人  他的一位祖先
It’s Lady Caroline de Winter,one of his ancestors.
真是个好主意  丹弗斯太太
Oh,well,that’s a splendid idea,Mrs.Danvers.I’m very grateful.
不胜感激
-一切尽在掌控之中吗  弗里思  -是的  先生  谢谢
-Everything under control,Frith? -Yes,sir,thank you.
抱歉问一句  先生  你是要扮演一位校长吗
Excuse me,sir,are you supposed to be a schoolmaster?
不是  这件只是我的旧方帽长袍
Oh,no. This is just my old cap and gown.
无疑是件不错的服装  先生  也很节俭
It certainly makes a very nice costume,sir.And economical,too.
是  我就是这么想的
Yes. That was the idea.
晚上好  罗伯特  不大适合开舞会的天气
Good evening,Robet. Not very good weather for the ball.
-是的  先生  -路上雾很大  很冷
-No,sir. -Very misty on the way and very chilly.
这顶假发太紧了  应该吃片阿司匹林止疼
Oh,this wig’s so tight they ought to send an aspirin with it.
好啊  扮演的是什么人物  亚当跟夏娃吗
Hello.What’s the idea? Adam and Eve?
-马克西  别恶心人了  -是大力士  老弟
Oh. Maxim,don’t be disgusting.
-我的杠铃呢  -什么
-Strongman.Where’s my weight thing? -What thing?
-你没落在车里吧  -没有  在那儿
You haven’t left it in the car,have you?
你是第一个下来的吗  那丫头呢
There it is.
-You were the first one down? -Yes.
她的着装要对外保密
Where’s the child?
Well,she’s keeping her costume a terrific secret.
不让我进她的房间
Wouldn’t even let me into her room.
真可爱
Oh,lovely.
我上去帮她一把
I’ll go up and give her a hand.
-我可以去喝一杯  -你穿成这样不会感冒吗
-I could do with a drink. -Won’t you catch a cold in that thing?
别傻了  这可是纯羊毛的  老弟
Don’t be silly. Pure wool,old boy.
等一下  先生  您忘了拿这个
-Pardon me,sir. You forgot this. -Thank you.
谢谢
我来了  亲爱的  是小贝  我来帮你的
Here I am,dear,it’s Bea. I’ve come to give a hand.
请别进来  比阿特丽斯  我不想任何人看到我的装束
MRS.DE WINTER: Oh,please don’t come in,Beatrice.
I don’t want anyone to see my costume.
不会很久吧
Oh.Oh,you won’t be long,will you?
因为总统随时都会驾临
Because the first people will be arriving any moment.
你肯定是缝在那儿吗
Now,you’re sure that’s where that should be?
是的  夫人  肯定没错
Yes,madam,it’s just right.
-很激动人心吧  -的确  夫人
-Isn’t it exciting? -Indeed it is,madam.
我一直听说曼陀丽庄园舞会
I’ve always heard of the Manderley ball,and now I'm really going to see one.
现在终于可以见识一回了
我肯定那儿无人能与您媲美  夫人
I'm sure there will be no one there to touch you,madam.
你真的那么认为吗  我的扇子在哪儿
Do you really think so? Now,where’s my fan?
你确定我看起来很好吗
Here.
-You’re sure I look all right? -You look ever so beautiful.
您看起来漂亮极了
走吧
Well,here goes.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
晚上好  德温特先生
Good evening,Mr.de Winter.
你知道自己干的什么好事
What the devil do you think you’re doing?
丽贝卡
Rebecca.
是那幅画  那幅画  画廊里的那副
But it’s the picture. The one in the gallery.
怎么了  我做了什么错事
-What is it? What have I done? -Go and take it off.
去  把衣服换掉  随便换什么都行  哪一件都行
It doesn’t matter what you put on. Anything will do.
你还站在那儿干吗  没听到我说的话吗
What are you standing there for? Didn’t you hear what I said?
布什先生跟莫里夫人到
ROBERT: Sir George and Lady Moore.
达德烈・泰南特上将跟玻班克夫人到
Dudley Tennant. Admiral and Lady Burbank.
我看着你下楼 就像一年前我看着她一样
I watched you go down,just as I watched her a year ago.
尽管穿着同样的衣服  但你无法与其相比
Even in the same dress,you couldn’t compare.
你知道的  你知道她曾穿过这件
You knew it.
可是你还故意建议我穿成这样
You knew that she wore it,and yet you deliberately suggested I wear it.
你为什么这么恨我
Why do you hate me? What have I done to you that you should ever hate me so?
我对你做了什么使你如此讨厌我
你设法取代她的位置  你让他娶你
You tried to take her place,you let him marry you.
我曾看着他的脸  他的眼神
I’ve seen his face,his eyes.
跟她去世后的前几个礼拜一样
They’re the same as those first weeks after she died.
我过去常常听见他整夜走来走去
I used to listen to him walking up and down,up and down,
一夜又一夜
all night long,night after night,
想起她  因失去她而遭受身心折磨
thinking of her,suffering torture because he’d lost her.
我不想知道  我不想知道
I don't want to know. I don’t want to know!
你以为你可以取代德温特太太
You thought you could be Mrs.de Winter,live in her house,walk in her steps,
住在她的房子里
take the thing that were hers. But she’s too strong for you.
走她所走过的阶梯  拿走属于她的东西
但她对于你来说太强大了  你无法打败她
You can’t fight her. No one ever got the better of her. Never. Never.
没人能胜过她  永远不会有  永远不会
她最终被打败  但不是被男人  或是女人所打败
She was beaten in the end,but it wasn’t a man,it wasn’t a woman.
-而是被大海  -别说了 别说了
It was the sea.
Oh,stop it. Stop it. Oh,stop it.
您太劳累了  夫人  我为您开扇窗户
You’re overwrought,madam. I’ve opened a window for you.
空气流通点  对您有好处的
A little air will do you good.
你干吗不走  干吗不离开曼陀丽
Why don’t you go? Why don’t you leave Manderley?
他不需要你
He doesn’t need you. He’s got his memories.
他有他的记忆
他不爱你  他只想跟她在一起
He doesn’t love you. He wants to be alone again with her.
你用不着留下
You’ve nothing to stay for.
你还活着干吗呢
You’ve nothing to live for,really,have you?
看下面  很容易  不是吗
Look down there.lt’s easy,isn’t it?
你为什么
Why don’t you? Why don’t you?
你何为什么
不跳下去 跳下去
Go on.
别害怕
Don’t be afraid.
(EXPLOSION)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
船只失事  是船只触礁
MAN 1: Shipwreck. MAN 2: Ship on the rocks!
是搁浅地的一艘船发射的烟火
-A ship aground,sending up rockets! -Shipwreck!
船难  大家快点  到海湾去  通知海岸巡逻队
MAN 2: Come on,everybody,down to the bay.
MAN 3: Notify the coast guard. MAN 4:She’s aground.
迈克西姆  迈克西姆
Maxim! Maxim!
-船靠岸了  -大家快点  快点
MAN 1: Ship ashore. MAN 2: Come on!Come on,everybody.
迈克西姆  迈克西姆
-MAN 2: Come on! Come on! -Maxim! Maxim!
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
噢
Oh!
本，你见到德温特先生了吗？
Ben,have you seen Mr.de Winter anywhere?
她不会回来了，是吗？你说过的
She won’t come back,will she? You said so.
谁？本？你说什么？
Who,Ben? What do you mean?
那个人
The other one.
弗兰克  有见过迈克西姆吗
-Frank,have you seen Maxim anywhere? -Not since about half an hour ago.
1个小时之前见过  我以为他去那间屋子了
I thought he’d gone up to the house.
没有  他根本没去过那间屋子
No,he hasn’t been in the house at all,
我担心他发生什么事了
and I’m afraid something might have happened to him.
弗兰克  怎么了  有什么不对劲吗
Frank,what’s the matter? Is anything wrong?
是有些事不对劲
-There is something wrong. -Well...
潜水员下去检查船底
The diver who went down to inspect the bottom of the ship
碰到另一艘船的船体
came across the hull of another boat. A little sailboat.
一艘小帆船
-弗兰克  那是   -是的  是丽贝卡的船
-Frank,is it... -Yes.
It’s Rebecca’s.
他们怎么认出它的
How did they recognize it?
他是个当地人  马上认出来了
He’s a local man. Knew it instantly.
那对可怜的迈克西姆太残忍了
It’ll be so hard on poor Maxim.
是的  又将所有的记忆带回来了
Yes.It’s going to bring it all back again,ask worse than before.
并且比之前更糟
他们为什么一定要找它呢
Why did they have to find it?
他们为什么不能让它安静地待在海底呢
Why couldn’t they have left it there in peace
at the bottom of the sea?
我最好去为那些人准备一些早餐
Well,I'd better get along and arrange some breakfast for the men.
好的  弗兰克  我去找迈克西姆
All right,Frank. I’ll go and look for Maxim.
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
迈克西姆
-Hello. -Maxim.
你整晚没睡
You haven’t had any sleep.
你原谅我了吗
-Have you forgiven me? -Forgiven you?
原谅你?  你做了什么事竟要我原谅
What have I got to forgive you for?
昨晚的事  有关服装的蠢事
For last night. My stupidity about the costume.
那个啊  我早忘了
Oh,that.
我对你发脾气了  是吗
I’d forgotten. I was angry with you,wasn’t I?
Hmm.
迈克西姆  难道我们不能一切从头开始
Maxim,can’t we start all over again?
我不奢求你爱我  我不作非分之想
I don’t ask that you should love me. I won’t ask impossible things.
让我做你的朋友和伙伴吧
I’ll be your friend,your companion. I’ll be happy with that.
那样我就很开心了
你很爱我  对吗
You love me very much,don’t you?
一切都晚了  宝贝
But it’s too late,my darling.
我们失去了绝无仅有的过幸福日子的机会
We’ve lost our little chance of happiness.
-不  迈克西姆  不  -是的  现在一切都结束了
-No,Maxim,no. -Yes.
It’s all over now.
事情终于发生了
The thing’s happened.
一直在我料想中的事
The thing I have dreaded day after day.
日复一日  夜复一夜
-Night after night. -Maxiw,what are you trying to tell me?
迈克西姆  你在说些什么
丽贝卡得胜了
Rebecca has won.
她的幽灵老是在你我之间徘徊
Her shadow has been between us all the time,keeping us from one another.
阻止我们在一起
她知道这事会发生
She knew that this would happen.
你在说什么啊
What are you saying?
他们派了一个潜水员下去  他找到了另一艘船
They sent a diver down.
-He found another boat. -Yes,I know. Frank told me.
我知道  弗兰克告诉我了  是丽贝卡的船
Rebecca’s boat. Oh,it’s terrible for you.I’m so sorry.
那对你来说太残酷了  对不起
潜水员还有另外一个发现
The diver made another discovery.
他弄破其中一个舱口  检查了船舱
Broke one of the ports and looked into the cabin.
里面有一具尸体
There was a body in there.
因此她并不是单独出海的
She wasn’t alone. There was someone sailing with her,
这说明当时她和另一个人一起出航
and you have to find out who it was,that’s it,isn’t it,Maxim?
你现在得查明这人是谁
就时这么一回事  对吗  迈克西姆
You don’t understand. There was no one with her.
你不明白  没人跟她一起出海
躺在船舱板上的是丽贝卡的尸体
It’s Rebecca’s body lying there on the cabin floor.
不
Oh,no.
被冲上埃奇库姆海岸的女人
The woman that was washed up at Edgecombe,
现在埋葬在家族墓地里的那个女人
the woman that is now buried in the family crypt,
不是丽贝卡
that was not Rebecca.
那是一个没人认领的无名女尸
That was the body of some unknown woman,
不知属于何方的女人尸体
unclaimed,belonging nowhere.
我认的尸  但我知道那不是丽贝卡
I identified it. But I knew it wasn’t Rebecca.
一切都是谎言
It wan all a lie.
我知道丽贝卡的尸体在哪里
I knew where Rebecca’s body was,
陈尸于海底的船舱板上
lying on that cabin floor on the bottom of the sea.
你怎么知道的  迈克西姆
How did you know,Maxim?
因为是我放在那儿的
Because I put it there.
现在你还能看着我的眼睛  告诉我你爱我吗
Will you look into my eyes and tell me that you love me now?
你看  我没说错
Yon see? I was right.
太晚了
It’s too late.
什么太晚了  不许再说这话
No,it’s not too late. You’re not to say that.
我爱你胜过世间的一切
I love you more than anything in thu world.
求你了  迈克西姆  吻我  求你了
-Oh,please,Maxim,kiss me,please. -No.
不  没用了  太迟了
It’s no use.It’s too late.
现在我们不能失去彼此
Oh,we can’t lose each other now. We must be together always.
我们必须永远在一起  没有秘密  没有阴影
No secrets,no shadows.
我们可能只剩几天  几个小时
We may only have a few days,a few hours.
迈克西姆  你之前为什么不告诉我
Maxim,why didn’t you tell me before?
有时我差点就讲出来了  但你那时的态度太冷漠
I nearly did sometimes,but you never seemed close enough.
我看出你在想念丽贝卡  还叫我怎么跟你亲热
How could we be close when I knew you were always thinking of Rebecca?
我看出你仍然爱着丽贝卡  怎么能要你再来爱我
How could I even ask you to love me,when I knew you Rebecca still?
你在胡说些什么  你这话什么意思
What are you talking about?
What do you mean?
每当你抚摸我的时候  我就想  你在拿我和丽贝卡相比
Whenever you touched me,I knew you were comparing me with Rebecca.
每当你对我说话  每当你看着我
Whenever you looked at we or spoke to me or walked with me in the garden,
或是同我一起在花园散步
我知道你在想
I knew you were thinking,“This I did with Rebecca,and this,and this.”
"我曾跟丽贝卡做过此事"
我说的不对吗
Oh it’s true,isn’t it?
你以为我爱丽贝卡?  你这么认为?
You thought I loved Rebecca? You thought that?
我恨她
I hated her.
我曾为她着迷
Oh,I was carried away by her,enchanted by her as everyone was.
为她心醉  跟所有人一样
我娶她的时候  别人都说我是世界上最幸运的男人
And when I was married,I was told I was the luckiest man in the world.
她长得那么美
She was so lovely,so accomplished,
很聪明  很风趣
so amusing.
大家都说
“She’s got the three things that really matter in a wife,”everyone said.
"一个妻子得有三种美德"
“Breeding brains and beauty.”
"教养  头脑和姿色"
我完全相信了他们的话
And I believed them. Completely.
但跟她在一起我从未有过幸福的时刻
But I never had a moment’s happiness with her.
她不懂爱
She was incapable of love
或是温柔或是宽容
or tenderness
or decency.
你不爱她?  你不爱她?
You didn’t love her. You didn’t love her.
还记得那天我开车带你上蒙特卡洛山顶的情景吗
Do you remember that cliff where you first saw me in Monte Carlo?
我曾跟丽贝卡一起到那儿度蜜月
Well. I went there with Rebecca on our honeymoon.
那就是我们相遇的地方
That’s where I found out about her,four days after we were married.
4天后我们就结婚了
她站在那儿笑
She stood there laughing,her black hair blowing in the wind
她的一头黑发在风中吹起
告诉我所有有关她的事
and told me all about herself.Everything.
所有事
我绝不会告诉别人
Things I’ll never tell a living soul.
我想要杀了她
I wanted to kill her.
那太容易了  记得那个悬崖吗
It would have been so easy.You remember the precipice?
我吓到你了  对吧  你以为我疯了
I frightened you,didn’t I? You thought I was mad.
说不定我也确实是个疯子
Perhaps I was. Perhaps I am mad.
跟魔鬼一起生活的人神智不可能健全  对吗
It wouldn’t make for sanity,would it? Living with the devil?
她说"我要跟你做笔交易"
“I’ll make a bargain with you,” she said.
"刚结婚4天你就想跟我离婚"
“You’d look rather foolish trying to divorce me now
"你看来相当的愚蠢"
after four days of marriage,
"所以我会扮演一位贤妻"
so I’ll play the part of a devoted wife,
"你珍贵的曼陀丽庄园的女主人"
mistress of your precious Manderley.
"只要你愿意
I’ll make it the most famous showplace is England,if you like,
我可以使这所宅子成为全国首屈一指的闻名去处"
"人们会跑来做客  羡慕我们 "
and people will visit us and envy us,
"在背地议论说我们俩是全英国最幸运  最美满的一对"
and say we’re the luckiest,happiest couple is the courtry.
"多大的愚弄  同时又是多大的成功"
What a grand joke it’ll be. What a triumph,”
我不该接受她那肮脏的交易  可我还是接受了
I should never have accepted her dirty bargain,but I did.
当时我过于年轻气盛  太过于在乎家族荣誉
I was younger then,and tremendously conscious of the family honor.
家族荣誉
Family honor.
她知道我宁愿牺牲一切
She knew that I'd sacrifice everything rather than stand up in a divorce court
也不要站在离婚法庭上
抛弃她  承认我们的婚姻是一场诈欺婚姻
and give her away,admit that our marriage was a rotten fraud.
你鄙弃我  是吗  连我自己都鄙弃我自己
You despise me,don’t you?
As I despise myself
你无法明白我什么感受  你能吗
You can’t understand what my feelings were,
can you?
我当然能明白  亲爱的  我当然明白
Of course I can,darling. Of course I can.
我遵守协议  显然她也是
Well,I kept the bargain and so did she,apparently.
她非常遵守游戏规则
Oh,she played the game brilliantly,
但不久  她慢慢地放肆起来
but after a while,she began to grow careless.
她在伦敦买了一套公寓  定期会在那儿住几天
She took a flat in London,and she'd stay away for days at a time.
她开始把自己的一帮狐群狗党请到这儿来
Then she started to bring her friends down here.
我向她提出过警告   她却毫不在意地一耸肩
I warned her,but she shrugged her shoulders.
说"这跟你有什么关系"
“What’s it got to do with you?” she said.
后来她竟同弗兰克调起情来  可怜的  忠实朋友
She even started on Frank.
Poor,faithful Frank.
她有个表哥  此人名叫费弗尔
Then there was a cousin of hers,a man named Favell.
我认识这个人  你去伦敦那天他来过
Yes. I know him. He came the day you went to London.
干吗不告诉我
Why didn’t you tell me?
我不想告诉你  我怕一说又会惹起你对丽贝卡的回忆
I didn’t like to.
I thought it would remind you of Rebecca.
惹起我的回忆?
Remind me?
难道我还要别人来惹起回忆吗
As if I needed reminding.
费弗尔常常来这间小屋探望她
Favell used to visit her here in this cottage.
我发现了此事  又一次提出警告
I found out about it,and I warmed her that if he come here again,
如果他再来这儿  我会开枪打死他们俩
I’d shoot them both.
某夜当我发现她悄悄从伦敦回来的时候
One night,when I found she had come back quietly from London,
我以为费弗尔跟她在一起
I thought that Favell was with her,
我知道我已无法再忍受
and I knew then that I couldn’t stand
这种充满污秽和欺诈的生活
this life of filth and deceit any longer.
我决定过来跟他们俩同归于尽
I decided to come down here and have it out with both of them.
但她独自一人
But she was alone.
她在盼望费弗尔的到来  但他没有
She was expecting Favell,but he hadn’t come.
她躺在长沙发椅上
She was lying on the divan,a large tray of cigarette stubs beside her.
一大盘掐灭的的烟头放在她旁边
她看上去生病了  不舒服
She looked ill,queer.
她突然起身
Suddenly,she got up,started to walk toward me.
开始向我走来
她说  "假如我有个孩子"
“When I have a child,”she said,“neither you nor anyone else
"你跟我都无法证明孩子不是你生的"
could ever prove it wasn’t yours.
"迈克斯  你想要个继承人  不是吗"
You would like to have an heir,wouldn’t you,Max,
"为了你钟爱的曼陀丽"
for your precious Manderley?”
她开始放声大笑
Then she started to laugh.
"多有趣  真是有趣到极点  妙不可言"
“How funny.How supremely,wonderfully funny.
"我将做一个十全十美的良母
I’ll be the perfect mother,just as I’ve been the perfect wife.
就像我是个十全十美的贤妻"
No one will ever know.
"谁也不会了解事实真相"
It ought to give you the thrill of your life,Max,
"那应该会使你的生活充满恐惧  迈克斯"
to watch my son grow bigger day by day
"看着我的儿子一天天长大 "
"一旦你死了  这一切将全部都归他所有"
and to know that when you die,Manderley will be his.”
她面对着我
She was face to face with me.
一只手插在口袋里
One hand is her pocket,the other holding a cigarette.
另一只手拿着香烟
微笑着
She was smiling.
"迈克斯  你将会怎么做"
“Well,Max?
What are you going to do about it?
"难道你要杀了我吗"
Aren’t you going to kill me?”
我猜想那一刻我失去理智了
I suppose I went mad for a moment.
我必须打她
I must have struck her.
她站在那儿盯着我
She stood staring at me.
她看起来几近得意洋洋
She looked almost triumphant.
然后她又开始微笑着向我走来
Then she started toward me again. Smiling.
突然她绊倒了
Suddenly,she stumbled and fell.
过了很久  当我低头看的时候
When I looked down,
好像 她正躺在地上
ages afterwards,it seemed,she was lying on the floor.
她将她的头往一块很重的船用索具上撞
She had struck her head on a heavy piece of ship’s tackle.
我依然记得当时纳闷她为何仍然在微笑
I rememder wondering why she was still smilling.
然后我才意识到她已经死了
Then I realized she was dead.
但你没有杀她  那是一场意外
But you didn’t kill her.It was an accident.
谁会相信我  我不知所措
Who would believe me?
我只知道我得做些什么事  任何事
I lost my head.
I just knew I had to do something. Anything.
我把她的尸体拖上了船
I carried her out to the boat.
外面一片漆黑  那晚上没有月光
It was very dark. There was no moon.
我把她的尸体拖进船舱
I put her in the cabin.
当船看起来离岸有一段安全距离的时候
When the boat seemed a safe distance from the shore,I took a spike,
我拿了一枚大钉
and drove it again and again through the planking of the hull.
然后一直猛击船板
我打开通海阀  水开始快速流进来
I had opened up the seacocks and the water began to come in fast.
我爬进小船里  划走
I climbed over into the dinghy and pulled away.
我看着船倾斜 下沉
I saw the boat heel over
and sink.
我折回到小海湾
I pulled back into the cove.
天开始下雨
It started raining.
迈克西姆  有别人知道这事吗
-Maxim,does anyone else know of this? -No. No one except you and me.
没有  除了你跟我  没人知道
我们必须去解释清楚
We must explain it.
因为那具尸体你之前从未见过
It’s got to be the body of someone you’ve never seen before.
不  他们一定认识她
No,they’re bound to know her. Her rings,bracelets she always wore.
她一直戴的戒指  手镯
他们会认出她的尸体  然后他们会记起另一个女人
They’ll identify her body then they’ll remember the other woman.
另一个埋葬在墓地里的女人
The other woman buried in the crypt.
如果他们发现那是丽贝卡
If they find out it was Rebecca,
你必须说你认错尸了
you must simply say you made a mistake about the other body.
因为你去埃奇库姆的那天  你正发病
That the day you went to Edgecombe,you were ill,
不能对自己的所作所为负责
you didn’t know what you were doind.
丽贝卡已死  那才是我们要记住的事
Rebecca’s dead.That’s what we’ve got to rememdar.Rebecca’s dead.
丽贝卡已死  她无法再开口讲话
She can't speak. She can't bear witness. She can't harm you anymore.
死无对证  她无法再伤害你了
天知地知  你知我知
We’re the only two people in the worlh thet know,Maxiw,yon and I.
我曾告诉过你  娶你为妻  是我多么自私的行为
I'd told you once that I’d done a selfish thing in marrying you.
现在你能明白什么意思了
You can understand now what I meant.
我爱你  亲爱的
I’ve loved you,my darling.
我会永远爱你
I shall always love you,
但我自始至终都知道丽贝卡最终会赢
but I’ve known all along
that Rebecca would win in the end.
不  不  她没有赢
No. no. She hasn't won.
不管现在发生什么事  她都没有赢
No matter what happens now,she hasn’t won.
(TELEPHONE RINGING)
喂?  喂
Hello?
喂  弗兰克  喂  弗兰克  是
Hello. Frank.
Hello,Frank. Yes.
谁  卡洛祖兰?
Who? Colonel Julyan?
告诉他我会尽快去那儿见他
Yes. Tell him I’ll meet him there as soon as I possibly can.
什么
What?
就说等我们确定事态后再谈
Well...
Say we could talk about that when we’re sure about the matter.
怎么了
What’s happened?
卡洛祖兰召见  他是国家郡警察局长
Colonel Julyan called.
He’s the chief constable of the county.
他被警察局请去停尸间
He’s been asked by the police to go to the mortuary.
他想知道我是否有可能认错了
He wanted to know if I could possibly have made a mistake
那具尸体
about that other body.
卡洛祖兰
Well,Colonel Julyan,apparently I did make a mistake about that other body.
显然我是认错尸体了
在那种情况之下  弄错很自然
Tha mistake was natural under the circumstances.
-再说  那时你状态不好  -我当时状态很好
-Besides,you weren’t well at the time. -That’s nonsense. I was perfectly well.
别担心  迈克西姆
Don’t let it worry you,Maxim. Nobody can blame you for making a mistake.
没人会因你搞错而责怪你
可惜的是  你得重新经受同样的事
The pity is,you’ve got to go through the same thing all over again.
-什么意思  -理所当然  将会有另一次审讯
What do you mean?
There’ll have to be another inquest,of course. Same formality and red tape.
同样的手续跟繁杂的公事程序
我希望你可以避免公众对它的主意
Wish you could be spared the publicity of it,but I’m afraid that's impossible.
但我恐怕那很难办到
Oh,yes,publicity.
对  公众的主意
我猜想德温特太太走下甲板去拿东西
I suppose Mrs.de Winter went below for something and a squall hit the boat
然后无人掌舵的船遭遇飓风
with nobody at the helm.
我猜想是那么回事  你觉得呢  克劳莱
I imagine that’s about the solution now,don’t you think so,Crawley?
是的  可能门卡住了  她无法再回到甲板上
Oh,yes. Probably the door jammed,and she couldn't get on deck again.
对  泰伯  那个造船的人
Yeah.
Tabb,the boat builder,will undoubtedly come to some such conclusion.
毫无疑问会得出一些这样的结论
为什么  他会知道些什么
Why,what would he know about it?
他现在在检查船只
Well,he’s examining the boat now. Purely as a matter of routine,you know.
完全按照惯例
明天我会进行审讯  迈克西姆  完全非正式的
I’ll be at the inquest tomorrow,Maxim,quite unofficially,you know.
等所有事都结束了  我们必须一起打场高尔夫
We must get together for a game of golf when it’s all over,eh?
-好  -再见
Bys-bye.
我有晚报  夫人
I have the evening papers,madam. Would you care to see them?
-要看看吗  -不  谢谢  弗里思
Oh,no thank you,Frith,
还有我想德温特先生也不会想看
and I prefer that Mr.de Winter weren’t troubled with them,either.
明白  夫人
I understand,madaw. Permit me to say that we’re all most distressed outside.
请允许我说句话  我们都承受着外界最巨大的困扰
谢谢  弗里思
Thank you,Frith.
恐怕那些新闻使丹弗斯太太受惊了
I’m afraid the news has been a great shock to Mrs. Danvers.
是啊  我多少预料到了
Yes,I rather expected it would be.
好像有一场验尸官审讯会  夫人
It seems there’s to be a coroner’s inquest,madam?
是的  弗里思  完全出于形式的审讯
Yes,Frith.It’s purely a formality
当然  夫人  我  我想说
Of course,madam. I...
如果我们任何人可能被传唤取证
I wanted to say that if any of us might be required to give avidence,
我将会很乐意做任何可能帮到家族的事
I should be only too pleased to do anything that might help the family.
谢谢  弗里思  我肯定
Oh,thank you,Frith,why,I...
德温特先生会很开心听到这席话
I’m sure Mr.de Winter will be very happy to hear it.
但我不认为有任何必要
But I don’t think anything will be necessary.
迈克西姆
Maxim.
亲爱的
Hello,darling.
迈克西姆  我 我担心明天在审讯会上你会做什么
Oh,Maxim,I’m worried about what you’ll do at the inquest tomorrow.
什么意思
What do you mean?
你不会发脾气吧
You won’t lose your temper,will you?
向我保证他们不会令你发火
Promise me that they won’t make you angry.
好的  亲爱的  我保证
All right,darling.I promise.
不管他问你什么  你不会失去理智
No matter what he asks you,you won’t lose your head?
别担心  亲爱的
Don’t worry,dear.
他们无法马上都搞定  对吗
They can’t do anything at once,can they?
No.
-那我们还剩一点时间在一起?  -是的
Then we’ve a little time left to be together.
Yes.
我想要跟你一起去审讯会
-I want to go to the inquest with you. -I’d rather you didn’t,darling.
我宁愿你不去  亲爱的
But I can't wait here alone.
但我无法一个人在这儿等着
我向你保证我不会给你带来任何麻烦的
I promise you,I won’t be any trouble to you.
不管发生什么事我必须待在你身边
And I must be near you so that no matter what happens,
我们片刻都不会分离
we won’t be separated for a moment.
好吧  亲爱的
All right,dear.
这整件事我都不在乎  除了你
I don’t mind this whole thing except for you.
我无法忘怀对你所做的事
I can't forget what it’s done to you.
自从它发生以来  我别无它想
I’ve been thinking of nothing else since it happened.
永远都回不去了
It’s gone forever,
我所爱的风趣  年轻貌美
that funny,young,lost look I loved.
永远不会再回来了
It won’t ever come back.
当我告诉你有关丽贝卡的事时  就被我抹杀了
I killed that when I told you about Rebecca.
都离开了
It’s gone.
在几个小时之内
In a few hours,you’ve grown so much older.
你变得更成熟了
迈克西姆  迈克西姆
(SOBBING)Oh,Maxim Maxim.
布莱克杰克・布莱德是他的名字
Black Jack Brady was his name.
我曾办过的最重要的案件
The most important arrest I ever made.
2年之前的案件
It must have been about two years ago now.
当然毫无疑问
Of course,there was no doubt about it. He was hung a month after I caught him.
我逮捕他1个月后  他被处以绞刑
Hello. Wait a minute.
等一下
他们带老伯米・本上来了
They’ve got old Balmy Ben up now.
你记得前任德温特太太吧
CORONER: You remember the late Mrs.de Winter,don’t you?
-她死了  -是的  我们知道
-She’s gone. -Yes,we know that.
她出海  被大海吞噬了
-She went in the sea. The sea got her. -That's right.That’s right.
对的 我们想要你告诉我们
Now we want you to tell us whether you were on the shore
那晚她出海  你是否在岸边
-that last night she went sailing. -Eh?
那晚她出去
Were you on the shore that last sight she went ou,when she didn't come back?
当她没返回的时候  你在岸边吗
我什么都没看见  我不想要去精神病院
I didn’t see nothing. I don’t want to go to the asylum.
那儿有恶人
Them cruel folks there.
没人要送你去精神病院
Now,nobody’s going to send you to the asylum.
我们只想要你告诉我们你所见到的
All we want you to do is tell us what you saw.
我什么也没看到
I didn’t see nothing.
快点  你有看到德温特太太那晚有上她的船吗
CORONER: Come,come.
Did you see Mrs.de Winter get into her boat that last night?
我什么都不知道  我不想去精神病院
I don’t know nothing.
I don’t want to go to the asylum.
好了  你可以走了
Very well.You may go.
你可以走了
-Eh? -You may go now.
泰伯先生  请上前
-Mr.Tabb,step forward,please. -Yes?
你所说的证供属实
The evidence you give will be the truth,the whole truth
绝无半点虚假
and nothing but the truth,so help you God?
我敢向上帝发誓
I do,so help me God.
前任德温特太太
The late Mrs.de Winter used to send her boat
过去常常把她的船送到你的船坞调修
-to your shipyard for reconditioning. -That’s right,sir.
-是的  长官  -你还记得任何
CORONER: Can you remember any occasion
-当她开船造成船只出任何意外的原因吗  -没有  长官
when she had any sort of accident with the boat?
我经常说德温特太太是个天生的水手
TABB: No,sir. I often said Mrs.de Winter was a born sailor.
当德温特太太走下甲板的时候  假设
Now,when Mrs.de Winter went below,as is supposed,
一场突如其来的飓风刮来
and a sudden gust of wind came down,
足以把船吹翻  不是吗
that would be enough to capsize the boat,wouldn’t it?
不好意思  长官  但还有其它的原因
Excuse we,sir. But there's a little more to it than that.
-什么意思  泰伯先生  -长官  我是说通海阀
-What do you mean,Mr.Tabb? -I mean,sir,the seacocks.
-什么是通海阀  -通海阀
What are the seacocks?
通海阀是船抽水的阀门
Sea...
The seacocks are the valves to drain out the boat.
当你在海上航行的时候  它们一直都是紧闭着的
They’re always kept tight closed when you’re afloat.
然后呢
Yes?
昨天当我检查船只的时候  我发现它们被打开了
Well,yesterday,when I examined that boat,I found they’d been opened.
-会有什么后果  -就是这样
Whet could be the reason for that?
Just this,that’s what flooded the boat and sunk her.
水渗进来把她淹没了
-你是指   -船根本就不是被吹翻的
Are you implying that boat never capsized at all?
长官  我知道这么不应该
I know it’s a terrible thing to say,sir,but in my opinion,
但依我所见  她是被淹没的
she was scuttled.
-还有洞  -什么洞
-And there’s them holes. -What holes?
-在她的翼板上  -你在说什么
-Is her planking. -What are you talking about?
当然  船已经在水下超过一年
Of course,that boat’s been underwater for over a year,
潮水使她的船撞到海脊
and the tide’s been knocking her against the ridge.
但是那些裂口看起来好像是她从里面造成的
But it seemed to me them holes looked as if she’d made them from the inside.
那么你认为她肯定是故意弄出来的
Then you believe she must have done it deliberately.
以她对船的知识  不可能会出此意外
Couldn’t have been no accident not with her knowledge of boats.
我相信  你对前任德温特太太很了解吧
You know the former Mrs.de Winter very well,I believe?
Oh,yes.
-是的  -你相信她会有自杀倾向吗
Would you have believed her capable of suicide?
不  坦白讲我不相信  但这很难说
No.Frankly,I would not. But you never can tell.
你可以下去了  泰伯先生
You way stand down,Mr.Tabb.
德温特先生  请
Mr.de Winter,please.
(PEOPLE MURMURING)
抱歉又把你拉回来做进一步审讯
(GAVEL POUNDING)
Sorry to drag you back for furthur questioning,Mr.de Winter.
你已经听到泰伯先生的陈述了
But you’ve heard the statement of Mr.Tabb.
我想知道你是否能给予帮助
I wonder if you can help us in any way.
-恐怖帮不上忙  -你能想到为何会有洞吗
I’m afraid not.
Can you think of any reason why there should be holes
前任德温特太太的船船板上的洞
in the planking of the late Mrs.de Winter’s boat?
我当然想不出任何原因
Well,of course I can't think of any reason.
之前有人曾跟你谈论过这些洞吗
Has anyone ever discussed these holes with you before?
自从船沉于海底以来
Well,since the boat has been at the bottom of the ocean,
I scarcely think that likely.
我几乎不可能想过
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
德温特先生  我想你相信我们都为你感到难过
Mr.be Winter,I want you to believe we all feel very deeply
for you in this matter.
但我不是为了自己的娱乐而举行这场审讯
But you must remember that I don’t conduct this inquiry
-显而易见  不是吗  -希望如此
for my own amusement.
-That’s rather obvious,isn’t it? -I hope that it is.
因为德温特太太单独出海
Well,since she went sailing alone,
难道我们就认为是她自己凿的那些洞吗
are we to believe that she drove those doles herself?
随你怎么想
You may believe what you like.
你可以启发我们关于德温特太太为何
Can you enlighten us as to why Mrs.de Winter should have wanted
想要结束她自己的生命
to end her own life?
我不知道什么原因
I know of no reason whatever.
德温特先生  不管有多么痛苦
Mr.de Winter,however painful it may be,
我必须问你一个非常私人的问题
I have to ask you a very personal question.
你跟前任德温特太太之间的感情很幸福吗
Were relations between you and the late Mrs.de Winter perfectly happy?
Were relations between you and the late Mrs.be Winter perfectly happy?
我不能再忍受了  你不妨现在就知道
I won’t stand this any longer! You might as well know now...
(GAVEL BANGING)
休庭直到午餐过后  德温特先生
CORONER:We’ll adjourn till after lunch.
Mr.de Winter,I presume you’ll be available for us then?
我相信那时你会为我们腾出时间来吧
我告诉过你该吃点早餐
I told you,you should have had some breakfast.
你只是饿了，没别的
You’re hungry. That’s what’s the matter with you.
弗里思先生说您也许想吃家里的午餐
Mr.Frith thought you might like to have some lunch from the house,
就让我带来了
and sent me with it.
不要紧，停在街角吧
No,that’s fine. Pull around the corner.
好的，先生
Very good,sir.
我真是太笨了  这样都会晕倒
Awfully foolish of me,fainting like that.
胡说  如果你没晕倒的话  我真的要发脾气了
Nonsense. If you hadn’t fainted like that,I’d have really lost my temper.
亲爱的  请小心点
Daring,please be careful.
亲爱的  在这儿等一会
Darling,wait here a few moments. I’ll see if I can old Frank.
-我去看看能否找到老弗兰克  -去吧  亲爱的
Of course,darling. Don’t worry about me.I’ll be all right.
-别担心我  我会没事的  -确定?  好的
Sure?
给  喝点这个  会舒服点的
Here,try a spot of this. Do you good.
谢谢
Thank you.
-你确定没事吗  -确定
-Are you all right? -Yes,of course.
-不会很久的  -行了
-I won’t be long. -Right you are.
Hello.
新娘子今天觉得如何呀
And how does the bride find herself today?
我是说  跟迈克西姆的婚姻并不如意吧
I say,marriage with Max is not exactly a bed of roses,is it?
我觉得你最好在迈克西姆回来之前离开
I think you’d better go before Maxim gets back.
他会吃醋?  我根本无权指责他
Oh,jealous,in he? Well,I can’t say I blame him.
但你不认为我是个大坏蛋  是吗
But you don’t think I’m the big bad wolf,do you?
我可不是  我是个非常平凡又和善可亲的人
I’m not,you know.I’m a perfectly ordinary,harmless bloke.
我觉得你对这件事处理的很好
And I think you’re behaving splendidly over all this. Perfectly splendidly.
非常的棒
自从上次见过你之后  你稍微变成熟了
You know,you’ve grown up a bit since I last saw you. It's no wonder...
-怪不得   -你想干吗  费弗尔
What do you want,Favell?
你好啊  迈克斯  你过得很好吧
Oh,hello,Max. Things are going pretty well for you,aren't they?
比你以前预期的更好
Better than you ever expected.
起初我还很担心你
I was rather worried about you at first. That's why I came down to the inquest.
所以我过来听审
我被你的关心所打动  但如果你不介意的话
Well,I'm touched by your solicitude.
But if you don't mind,we’d rather like to have our lunch.
我们想要用午餐了
Lunch? I say,what a jolly idea. Rather like a picnic,isn’t it?
午餐  多么好的主意啊  更像是野餐  不是吗
对不起  是否介意我把这个放在这儿
I’m so sorry. Do you mind if I put this there?
迈克斯  老兄
You know,Max,old boy,I really think I ought to talk things over with you.
我真的觉得我应该跟你商量点事
商量什么
Talk what things over?
首先  那些船板上的那些洞
Well,those holes in the planking,for one thing.
那些洞是从里面被凿开的
Those holes that were drilled from the inside.
-穆勒  -什么事  先生
-Oh,Mullen? -Yes,sir?
可以把我的车开去加油吗
Would you,like a good fellow,have my car filled with petrol?
-快没油了  -好的  先生
-It’s almost empty. -Very good,sir.
-还有  穆勒  把门关上吧  -是的  先生
-And,Mullen,close the door,will you? -Yes,sir.
烟熏到你了吗
Does this bother you?
老兄  我有种强烈的感觉
You know,old boy,I buys a strong feeling that before the day’s out,
不出一天  有些人将会
somebody’s going to make use of that rather expressive,
用婉转的方式表达一般所说的"谋杀"
though somewhat old-fashioned term,“foul play.”
你们觉得无聊吗
Am I boring you with all this?
没有吗  很好
No?
迈克斯  我发觉自己处于一个相当尴尬的立场
Good.Well,you see,Max,I find myself in a rather awkward position.
你只要看一下这封信就明白了  是丽贝卡写的
You’ve only got to read this note to understand.It’s from Rebecca.
还有  她真是有先见之明
And,what’s more,she had the foresight to put a date on it.
她去世的那天写给我的
She wrote me the day she died.
不巧地是  那天晚上我去参加派对了
Incidentally,I was at a party on that night
所以直到第二天我才看到
so I didn’t get it until the next day.
为什么你觉得我会对这封信感兴趣呢
And what makes you think that note would interest me?
我不会跟你讨论信的内容
Oh,I’m not gonna bother you with the contents now.
但我可以肯定那不是一个打算当晚
But I can assure you that it is not the note of a woman
自杀的女人会写的信
who intends to drown herself that same night.
顺便说一下  你怎么处理以前的骨骸
By the way,what do you do with old bones? Bury them?
葬了它们  还是怎样
然而  暂且
However,for the time being...
迈克斯
You know,Max,I’m getting fed up with my job as a motorcar salesman.
我真的受够了做汽车销售员的工作
我不知道你是否曾经经受过那种感觉
I don’t know if you’ve ever experienced the feeling
开着一辆价值不菲却不属于你的汽车
of driving an expensive motorcar which isn’t your own?
但那真的会气死人
But it can be very,very exasperating.
你知道我什么意思  你想拥有自己的车
You know what I mean. You want to own the car yourself.
我经常问自己  迁居到乡下会是什么样
I oftan wonder what it would be like to ratire to the country.
拥有一个有着几英亩猎场的漂亮的小地方
Have a nice little place with a few acres of shooting.
我从未弄明白那要花一年的时间
I’ve never figured out what it what it would cost a year,
但我想要跟你谈谈
but I’d like to talk about it with you.
我想听听你的建议
I’d like to have your advice on how to live comfortably without hard work.
怎样能不用努力工作而过着舒适的生活
你好  费弗尔  你找我吗  迈克西姆
Hello,Favell. You looking for me,Maxim?
是的  费弗尔先生跟我有点事要谈
Yes.
Mr.Favell and I have a little business transaction on hand.
我想我们最好去小酒馆解决
I think we had better conduct it over at the inn.
那儿也许有包间
They may have a private room there.
待会儿见
Well,see you later.
去找朱利安上校  告诉他我要马上见他
Find Colonel Julyan. Tell him I want to see him immediately.
走吧  费弗尔
Come on.Favell.Let’s go.
请问有包间吗
-Have you a private room,please? -Of course,sir. Through there,sir.
-当然有  先生  那边请  先生  -谢谢
希望这位就是德温特先生
Hope this will do,Mr.de Winter.
很豪华啊 的确像是豪华的酒馆
Splendid.Splendid. Exactly like the Ritz.
-要点餐吗  先生们  -给我一杯大的白兰地苏打水
Any orders,gents?
Yes. You might bring me a large brandy and soda.
你呢  迈克斯  一杯酒我还请得起
How about you,Max? Have one on me. I feel I can afford to play host.
-谢谢  好的  -来两杯  可以吗  好伙计
Thanks. I don’t mind if I do.
-好的  先生  -德温特先生在哪里
Make it two,will you,like a good fellow?
-Very good,sir. -COLONEL JULYON:Where’s Mr.de Winter?
开门就是了  先生
PROPRIETOR: Through the other door,sir.
朱利安上校  他是费弗尔先生
Colonel Jnlyan,this is Mr.Favell.
我认识朱利安上校  我们是老相识了  是吧
Oh,I know Colonel Jnlyan. We’re old friends,aren’t we?
既然你们是老相识
Since you’re old friends,I assume you also know
我猜想你也知道他是这儿的警方首脑
he’s head of the police here.
我想他会有兴趣听你的陈述
He might be interested to hear your proposition. Tell him all about it.
说吧  告诉他所有事
I don't know what you mean. I merely said I hoped to give up selling cars
我只不过说我希望放弃卖车的工作并退休
事实上  他提出  如果我酬谢他的话
and retire into the country.
Actually,he offered to withhold a vital piece of evidence from the inquest
他会保留一份很重要的证据
if I made it worth his while.
我只是想见识一下司法公正  上校
I only want to see justice done,Colonel.
那位造船人的证据
Now,that boatbuilder’s evidence suggested certain possible theories
指出某些有关丽贝卡之死的看法
concerning Rebecca’s death. One of them,of course,is suicide.
其中之一  当然  是自杀
Now I have a little note here which I consider
我这儿有封信可以驳回那个可能性
puts that possibility quite out of court.
-读一下吧  上校  -"亲爱的  杰克"
Read it,Colonel.
"我刚看完医生  我要马上回曼陀丽"
“Jack,darling,
I’ve just seen the doctor and I’m going down to Manderley right away.
"我整晚都会待在小屋"
I shall be at the cottage all this evening
"并为你留着门"
and shall leave the door open for you.
"我有要事相告  丽贝卡上"
I have something terribly important to tell you.
那像是一个决定自杀的女人
Rebecca.”
Now,does that look like the note of a woman
会写的信吗
who had made up her mind to kill herself?
除此之外  上校
And apart from that,do you mean to tell me
难道说如果你要自杀的话
that if you wanted to commit suicide,you would go to all the trouble
你会特意出海
of putting out to sea is a boat,and then take a hammer and chisel
还拿一把榔头跟凿子
and laboriously knock holes through the bottom of it?
然后费劲凿洞弄穿底部吗
Come,Colonel.As an officer of the law,
得了吧  上校  作为一个执法官
你难道不觉得有些许嫌疑吗
don’t you feel there are some slight grounds for suspicion?
-谋杀的嫌疑?  -还能有什么
-Of murder? -What else?
你认识迈克斯很久了  所以你知道他是个老古董
You’ve known Max a long time. So you know he’s the old-fashioned type,
会誓死I卫他的荣誉或是扼杀它
who’d die to defend his honor,or who’d kill for it.
纯粹是敲诈
It’s blackmail,pure and simple.
Blackmail is not so pure,nor so simple.
It can bring a lot of trouble to a great many people.
还有敲诈者有时最终会将自己送进监牢
And the blackmailer sometimes find himself in jail at the end of it.
我明白  你会为德温特辩解
Oh,I see.You’re going to hold de Winter’s hand through all this.
只因为他是这儿的大亨
Just because he’s the big noise around here
而且你是他的座上客  他是你的酒肉朋友
and he’s actually permitted you to dine with him.
说话小心点  费弗尔  你所指控的是谋杀
Be careful,Favell. You’ve brought an eccusation of murder.
-你有任何证人吗  -我确实有一个证人
-Have you any witnesses? -I do have a witness.
那就是本
It’s that fellow,Ben.
如果那个愚蠢的验尸官是个内行的话
If that stupid coroner hadn’t been as much of a snob as you are,
他会看出那个傻子在隐瞒些事
he’d have seen that half-wit wes hiding something.
本为何要隐瞒
And why should Ben do that?
因为丽贝卡跟我  我们曾抓住他
Because we caught him once,Rebecca and I,
他透过小屋的窗户偷看我们
peering at us through the cottage window.
丽贝卡威胁说要把他送到精神病院  所以他不敢说
Rebecca threatened him with the asylum. That's why he was afraid to speak.
但他一直闲晃  所以他肯定看到过整件事
But he was always hanging about. He must have seen this whole thing.
听起来就够荒谬的
It’s ridiculous,even listening to all this.
你们所有人像是个小工会  不是吗
You’re like a little trade union,all of you,aren’t you?
如果我的猜测是对的话  克劳莱
And if my guess in right,Cramley,
在你的内心深处对我有点敌意  不是吗
there’s a bit of malice in your soul toward me,isn’t there?
克劳莱追不到丽贝卡
Crawley didn’t have much success with Rebecca,
但这次他应该会更幸运
but he ought to have more luck this time.
新娘子会感激你伸出友谊的臂膀  克劳莱
And the bride will be grateful for your fraternal arm,Crawley,
一个多星期之后
in a week or so. Every time she faints,in fact.
-每次她晕倒  实际上  -德温特
-De Winter! -Maxiw,please!
-迈克西姆  拜托  -德温特
你会为你的臭脾气付出代价的  迈克斯
That temper of yours will do you in yet,Max.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
打扰一下  先生们  还需要什么吗
Excuse me,gentlemen.
-Now is there anything else? -Yes.
需要  你可以拿支镇静剂给德温特先生
You might bring Mr.de Winter a sedative.
-不  不用了  什么都不需要  出去吧  -好的  先生
-No,no. Nothing at all. Just leave us. -Very good.
费弗尔  我们来做个了结
Now,Fevell,let’s get this business over.
你好像对整件事做过仔细的了解
As you seew to have worked out the whole thing so carsfully,
也许你可以给我们提供一个动机
perhaps you can provide us also with a motive.
我知道你会提出这个问题  上校
I know you were going to bring that up,Colonel.
我曾拜读过很多侦探小说
I’ve read enough detective stories to know that there must always be a motive.
从而知道肯定会有杀人动机
是否容我失陪一下  我会提供动机的
And if you’ll all excuse me,I might supply that,too.
我希望你先回家  你不该待在这儿经受这一切
I wish you’d go home. You ought not to he here through all this.
拜托让我留下  迈克西姆
Please let me stay. Maxim.
无疑地  朱利安上校  你不会允许这个家伙
Surely,Colonel Julyan,you’re not going to allow this fellow to...
我对费弗尔的看法与你一样不好  克劳莱
My opinion of Favell is no higher than yours,Crawley.
但做为警察
But in my official capacity,I have no altnrnative
我别无选择唯有继续听他的指控
But to pursue his accusations. I entirely agree with you,Colonel.
我完全同意你的说法  上校
在一定程度上像这件如此严重的案件  我们必须
In matters as serious as this,we must make sure of every point
弄清楚每一个要点  寻求各种途径
and explore every avenue.
事实上  如果我千方百计捏造事实
And in fact,if I may coin a phrase,leave no stone unturned.
她来了  缺少的环节
Here she is,the missing link,the witness who will help supply the motive.
将帮忙提供动机的证人
朱利安上校  丹弗斯太太  我相信你认识所有人
Colonel Julyan Mrs.Danvers. I believe you know everyone else.
要坐下吗
Won’t you sit down?
无意冒犯  上校  但我想由我来问丹尼
No offense,Colonel,but I think I’ll put this to Danny.
她会更容易明白  丹尼  谁是丽贝卡的医生
She’ll understand it more easily.
Danny,who was Rebecca’s doctor?
德温特太太一直都看村里的麦克林医生
Mrs.de Winter always had Dr.McClean from the village.
你听到了  我是说丽贝卡在伦敦的医生
Now,you heard. I said Rebecca’s doctor in london.
我对此一无所知
I don’t know anything about that.
别跟我打哈哈  你知道丽贝卡的所有事
Oh,don’t give me that,Danny.You knew everything about Rebecca.
你知道她与我恋爱  不是吗
You knew she was in love with we,didn’t you?
你肯定没有忘记过去她跟我
Surely you haven’t forgotten the good times she and I used to have
在下面小屋里的美好时光
down at the cottage on the beach.
她有权消遣她自己  不是吗
She had a right to amuse herself,didn’t she?
对她来说  爱情是一场游戏  它令她发笑
Love was a game to her. Only a game. It make her laugh,I tell you.
她过去常常坐在她的床上嘲笑你
She used to sit and rock with laughter at the lot of you.
你可想得出任何理由
Can you think of why Mrs.de Winter should have taken her own life?
对德温特夫人的自杀作出解释吗
不  不  我拒绝相信此事  我知道她的所有事
No,no. I refuse to believe it.
我不会相信她是自杀
I knew everything about her and I won’t believe it.
听到了吧  不可能  她跟我一样
There. You see?It’s impossible. She knows that an well as I do.
听我说  丹尼  我们知道丽贝卡去伦敦看医生
Now,listen to me,Danny.
We know that Rebecca went to a doctor in London
-是谁  -我不知道
on the last day of her life. Who was it?
我明白  丹尼
I don’t know.
I understand,Danny
你以为我们要求你泄露丽贝卡生命的秘密
You think we’re asking you to reveal secrets of Rebecca’s life.
你想要保护她  但我也是
You’re trying to defend her.But that's what I’m doing.
我想要澄清她自杀的嫌疑
I’m trying to clear her name of the suspicion of suicide.
丹弗斯太太  有人指出
Mrs.Danvers,it has been suggested
德温特太太是被蓄意谋杀的
that Mrs.de Winter was deliberately murdered.
你简单说明一下  丹尼
There you buys it in e nutshell,Danny.
但还有一件事  你要说的凶手的名字
But there’s one more thing you’ll want to know,the name of the murderer.
一个可爱的名字
It’s a lovely name that rolls off the tongue so easily.
乔治・福斯科・马克西米利安・德温特
George Fortescue Maximilian de Winter.
是有位医生  德温特太太有时私下让他看病
There was a dactor.
她过去常常让他就医  即使在她结婚之前也是
Mrs.de Winter sometimes went to him privately.
She used to go to him even before she was married.
丹尼  我们不想听你回忆旧事  他叫什么名字
We don’t want reminiscences,Danny.What was his name?
贝克医生  谢菲德小镇  戈德霍克路165号
Dr.Baker. 165 Goldhawk Road,Shepherd’s Bush.
听见了吧  上校  那儿将是你找到动机的地方
There you are,Colonel. There’s where you’ll find your motive.
去问贝克医生  他会告诉你为何丽贝卡去看他
Go and question Dr.Baker. He’ll tell you why Rebecca went to him.
去确认她怀孕的事实
To confirm the fact that she was going to have a child.
孕育一个可爱的  满头卷发的小孩子
A sweet,curly-headed little child.
那不是真的 她会告诉我要孩子的事的
It isn’t true. It isn’t true. She would have told me.
她曾告诉过迈克斯  迈克西姆知道自己不是经手人
She told Max about it. Max knew he wasn’t the father.
所以  他像传统的绅士一样  杀了她
So,like the gentleman of the old school that he is,he killed her.
恐怕我们得去问问贝克医生
COLONEL JULYAN:I’m afraid we shall have to question this Dr.Baker.
知道了 但为了安全起见  我想我也要一起前往
Hear,hear. But for safety’s sake,I think I’d like to go along,too.
遗憾地是  我猜想你有权要求一起前往
Yes. Unfortunately,I suppose you have the right to ask that.
我要去见一下验尸官
I’ll see the coroner and have the inquest postponed
让审讯推迟  直到找到进一步证据为止
pending farther evidence.
难道你不担心囚犯 可能会逃跑吗
I say,aren’t you rather afraid that the prisoner,shall we say,might bolt?
记住我的话  他不会那么做的
You have my word for it that he will not do that.
再见  迈克斯  一起走吧  丹尼
Toodle-oo,Max. Come along,Danny.
别打扰这对不幸福的夫妇一起度过最后的时光了
Let’s leave the unhappy couple to speed their last moments together alone.
你确定不要我跟你一起去吗  迈克西姆
Are you sure you don’t want me to go with you,Max?
是的  亲爱的  那会使你疲惫不堪的
No,darling. It’ll be very tiring for you.
我一大早就会回去了
I’ll be back the very first thing in the morning.
我会不眠不休地赶回去
-And I won’t even stop to sleep. -I’ll be waiting for you.
我等你
-好了吗  迈克西姆  -好了
-Ready,Maxim? -Yes.
你们俩开前面  我跟着费弗尔
You two go on ahead. I'll follow with Favell.
贝克医生
COLONEL JULYAN:Dr.Baker,you may have seen
最近你也许在报纸上看过德温特先生的名字
Mr.de Winter’s name in the pepers renently.
是的 跟一具在船上被发现的尸体有关
Yes. Yes. In connection with the body that was found in a boat.
我太太看了所有报道  令人伤心的案件
My wife was reading all about it. A very sad case. My condolences.
-同情   -这将花去数小时  容我
FAVELL: This is going to take hours. Let me...
别费心了  费弗尔  我想我可以告诉贝克医生
Don’t bother,Favell. I think I can tell Dr.Baker.
我们想要了解某些有关
We’re trying to discover certain facts
前任德温特太太去世当天的活动真相
concerning the late Mrs.de Winter’s activities on the day of her death.
去年  10月12号  如果你记得的话  我想你告诉我
October the 12th,last year
I want you to tell me if you can,
那天是否有叫这个名字的人拜访过你
if anyone of that name paid you a visit on that date?
非常抱歉  恐怕我帮不上忙
I’m awfully sorry. I’m afraid I can't help you.
我是记得有个叫德温特的人
I should have remembered the name de Winter.
但我从未给一个叫德温特太太的人看过病
I’ve never attended a Mrs.de Winter in my life.
你怎么可能记得所有你病人的名字
FAVELL: How can you possibly tell all your patients'names?
如果你想的话  我可以从预约本上找找
I can look it up is my engagement diary if you like.
-你是说10月12号吗  -是的
-Did you say the 12th of October? -COLONEL JULYAN:Yes.
找到了  没有  没有叫德温特的
Here we era.
No. No de Winter
-你确定吗  -这是那天所有的预约
Are you sure?
Well,here are all the appointments for that day.
"罗丝  坎贝尔  斯蒂尔  佩里诺  丹弗斯  马修 "
Ross,Campbell Steadall,Perrino Danvers...
丹尼  见鬼
-Danny? What the devil? -Would you read that name again?
可以再念一遍名字吗  你念到丹弗斯?
Did you say Danvers?
是的  3点有位丹弗斯太太的预约
Yes. I have a Mrs.Danvers for 3:00.
她长什么样  你还记得吗
What did she look like? Can you remember?
记得  我记得很清楚  她是位非常漂亮的女人
Yes,I remember her quite well. She was e very beautiful woman.
高挑个儿  黑黑的脸蛋  穿着很精致
-Tall dark,exquisitely dressed. -CRAWLEY: Rebecca.
-是丽贝卡  -那位女士肯定用了化名
The lady must have used an assumed name.
是吗  真是令人吃惊  我认识她很久了
Is that so?
This is a surprise. I’ve known her a long time.
她得了什么病
What was the matter with her?
尊敬的先生  我们有职业操守
Well,there are certain ethics.
你可能提供德温特太太自杀的原因  贝克医生
Could you supply a reason Dr.Baker,for Mrs. de Winter’s suicide?
是谋杀  她怀孕了  不是吗
For her murder,you mean?
She wan going to have a kid,wasn't she? Come on. Out with it!
快点  快说
Tell me,what else would a woman of her class be doing in a dump like this?
她这种高尚的女人怎么会做这样污秽的事
我以警方的名义来访  对我来说有必要
I take it the official nature of this visit makes it necessary for me to...
使你相信如果没必要的话
I assure you we’d not be troubling you if it were not necessary.
我们就不会来打扰你了
你们想知道我是否可以指出任何有关
You want to know if I can suggest any motive
德温特太太会自杀的动机?
as to why Mrs.de Winter should have taken her life?
我想可以
Yes,I think I can.
那位自称丹弗斯太太的女人得了很严重的病
The woman who called herself Mrs.Danvers was very seriously ill.
我不是怀孕了吗
She was not going to have a child?
她以为是  但我的诊断却不同
That was what she thought. My diagnosis was different.
我让她去找一位知名的专科医生做检查  照X光
I sent her to a well-known specialist for an axamination and x-rays.
而那天她是拿她的检查报告来给我看的
And on this date,she returned to me for his report.
我记得她站在这儿拿着她的X光片
I rememder her standing here holding out her hand for the photograph.
她说  "我想知道真相"
“I want to know the truth,”she said.
"我不要听冠冕堂皇的话"
“I don't want soft words and a bedside manner.
"如果有病  你可以马上告诉我"
If I’m for it you can tell me right away.”
我知道她不是那种听了假话会信以为真的人
I knew she was not the tyge to accept a lie.
她要听实话  所有我就告诉她了
She’d asked for the truth,so I let her have it.
她跟我道谢之后  我再也没有见过她了  所有我猜想
She thanked me. I never saw her again,so I assumed...
-她得了什么病  -癌症
-What was wrong with her? -Cancer.
是的  癌症晚期
Yes,the growth was deep-rooted.
动手术也完全无济于事
An operation would have been no earthly use at all.
要不了多久  她就得靠吗啡来止痛了
In a short time,she would have been under morphia.
除了等死  没什么可做的了
There was nothing that could be done for her,except wait.
当你告诉她病情的时候  她有说什么吗
MAXIM:Did she say anything when you told her?
她怪异地微笑着
DR.BAKER:She smiled in a queer sort of way.
你的妻子是个很棒的女人  德温特先生
Your wife was a wonderful woman,Mr.de Winter.
对了  我记得她说了一些
And,oh,yes,I remember she said something
当时令我觉得非常奇怪的话
that struck me as being very peculiar at the time.
当我告诉她只剩几个月的时候
When I told her it was a matter of months,she said,
她说  "不  医生  不用那么久"
“Oh.no. Doctor,not that long.”
很好  你已经告诉我们所有我们想知道的事了
You’ve been very kind. You’ve told us all we wanted to know.
我可能会需要一次正式的审查
We shall need an official verification.
-审查?  -是的  以确定自杀的裁决
-Verification? -Yes.
-To confirm the verdict of suicide. -DR.BAKER: I understand.
我明白  可以请你们喝杯雪利酒吗
Can I offer you gentlemen a glass of sherry?
不用了  太客气了  我想我们该走了
COLONEL JULYAN: No,that's very kind? I think we ought to be going.
谢天谢地我们终于知道真相了
Thank heaven we know the truth.
可怕的事  太可怕了
Dreadfnl thing. Dreadful.
像她这样一位年轻貌美的女人  难怪
Young and lovely woman like that. No wonder...
我一点也不明白  丹尼肯定也是
I never had the remotest idea. Neither did Danny,I’m sure.
希望我是喝醉酒了
I wish I had a drink.
我们还需要再做进一步审讯吗  朱利安上校
Will we be needed at the inquest any further,Colonel Julyan?
不用了  我看得出迈克西姆也不想再被骚扰了
No,no.I can see to it that Maxim’s not troubled any further.
-谢谢  长官  -准备走了吗  上校
-Thank you,sir. -You ready to start,Colonel?
不用  谢谢  今晚我要待在城里
No,thank you. I’m staying in town tonight.
费弗尔  敲诈勒索可不是什么好行当
And let me tell you,Favell,blackmail in not much of a profession.
我们这一带的人知道该怎么对付讹诈
And we know how to deal with it in our part of the world,
尽管在你看来这或许有点新鲜
strange as it may seem to you.
我的确不知道你在讲什么
I’m sure I don’t know what you’re talking about.
上校  但是如果你什么时候需要买车的话就告诉我
But if you ever need a new car,Colonel,just let me know.
不知该如何感谢你帮忙我们解决了这件事
It’s impossible to thank you for your kindness to us through all this.
千言万语尽在不言中
You know what I feel without my saying it.
别客气  别说感谢的话了
Not at all. Put the whole thing behind you.
最好先通知你太太  她会担心的
But let your wife know. She'll be getting worried.
是  我会马上打电话给她  然后就直接回曼陀丽
Yes,of course. I’ll phone her at once
and we’ll get straight down to Manderley.
再见  克劳莱  迈克西姆是个很好的朋友
Goodbye,Crawley Maxim’s got a great friend.
-弗兰克  -什么事  迈克西姆
-Frank. -Yes,Maxim?
有些事你不知道
-There’s something you don’t know. -Oh,no,there isn’t.
不  我都知道
我没有杀她  弗兰克
I didn’t kill her, Frank.
但我现在明白当她告诉我孩子的事时
But I know now that when she told me about the child,
她想要我杀了她
she wanted me to kill her.
她故意撒谎  她早已预料到整件事
She lied on purpose. She foresaw the whole thing.
所以当她 她站在那儿笑
That’s why she stood there laughing when she...
别再想了
Don’t think about it anymore.
谢谢你  弗兰克
Thank you,Frank.
喂  丹尼  我只是想要告诉你个消息
Hello,Danny.I just wanted to tell you the news.
丽贝卡把我们俩都耍了  她得了癌症
Rebecca held out on both of us. She had cancer.
是的  是自杀
Yes,suicide.
从此以后迈克斯跟他亲爱的小新娘
Now Max and that dear little bride of his
将会继续幸福地在曼陀丽生活
will be able to stay on at Manderley and live happily ever after.
再见  丹尼
Bye-bye,Danny.
-这是你的车吗  先生  -是的
-This your car,sir? -Yes.
可以马上开走吗  这不是停车位
Will you be going soon? This isn’t a parking place,you know.
不是吗  如果想的话
Oh,isn’t it? Well,people are entitled to leave cars outside if they want to.
我就有权把车停在外面
真遗憾  你们这些家伙没什么好事可做的
It’s a pity some of you fellows haven’t anything to do.
你打电话回去的时候  她说会等你回来吗
When you phoned,did she say she’d wait up?
我让她先睡  可她不听
I asked her to go to bed,but she wouldn't hear of it.
真希望能开得再快点儿
I wish I could get some more speed out of this thing.
你在担心什么  迈克西姆
Is something worrying you,Maxim?
事情有点不对头  有点不妙
I can’t get over the feeling something’s wrong.
-弗兰克  -怎么了  干吗停车
-Frank. -What’s the matter? Why did we stop?
现在几点了
What’s the time?
这表不准  肯定是3、4点了  怎么了
Well,this clock’s wrong. It must be 3:00 or 4:00. Why?
那不可能是破晓黎明
That can’t be the dawn breaking over there.
因为是冬天  所以你看到北极光了吧
It’s in the winter that you see the northern Iights,isn’t it?
那不是北极光  那是曼陀丽
That’s not the northern lights. That’s Manderley.
弗里思  弗里思  德温特太太呢  她在哪儿
Frith! Frith!
Mrs.de Winter. Where is she?
-我想我看到过她  先生  -在哪儿
-I thought I saw her,sir -Where?
迈克西姆
Maxim!
-谢天谢地你回来了  -你没事吧  快告诉我
Thank heavens you’ve come back to me!
-Are you all right,darling? -Oh,yes,I am.
-没事  我没事  -你没事吧
Are you all right?
是丹弗斯太太放的火  她疯了
Mrs.Danvers,she’s gone mad.
她说宁愿毁掉曼陀丽
She said she’d rather destroy Manderley than see us happy here.
也不要看着我们幸福地住在这儿
看  快看西厢
ROBERT: Look! The west wing!